<?xml version="1.0" standalone='yes' ?>
	<pages>	
		<backgroundImages>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/hana-background-3.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Hamoa Beach &ndash; consistently recognized as one of the top beaches in the world.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/hana-background-2.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Something magical happens when you meditate outside by the ocean.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/hana-background-1.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Sunrise view from Travaasa Hāna&rsquo;s Sea Ranch Cottages</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/hana-background-4.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Sunrise yoga with stunning ocean views and warm breezes.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>		
		</backgroundImages>
		<hana>
			<secondaryPages>
				<page section="2" primarySection="0" root="true" secondaryNav="true" id="0" position="1"  sitemapId="4.0" sitemapTitle="TRAVAASA HĀNA">
					<title>Hāna Overview</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>travaasa-hana-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Travaasa Hāna</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa Hāna is a unique property that offers an all-inclusive stay and an a la carte option.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, hawaii, hawaii travel, hawaii resorts, hawaii hotel, Hawaiian hotel, maui resort, maui hotel, maui spa, experiential, authentic hawaii, authentic hawaiians</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1 position="1">Maui’s Last Truly Hawaiian Place</h1>
					<copy position="1"><![CDATA[<p>Travaasa Hāna is a destination hotel unlike anywhere else in the world. Gracious in every sense of the word, from our staff to accommodations, dining, experiences, scenery and much more. We invite you to discover it for yourself.</p>
					<h2 class="landing_page">Your Travaasa begins with two accommodation paths. Both unique. Both embracing an authentic sense of old Hawai'i.</h2>
					<br />
					<div class="hana_promo_content" align="center"><a href="http://travaasa.com/hana/#/hana-rates-and-packages-sea-ranch-cottages">LIMITED OFFER: Fall in Love with Travaasa Hāna and save 33%</a></div>
					<br />
					<div class="hana_home_promo_left">
						<img src="/images/site/hana-SRC-path.jpg" alt="Sea Ranch Cottages" />
						<div class="hana_promo_content">
							<h2 class="landing_page">Sea Ranch Cottages</h2>
							<p>These havens nestled near the ocean and include everything that Travaasa and &ldquo;Heavenly Hāna&rdquo; has to offer. Choose this path for the full Travaasa experience. <i>Guests age 16 and older are welcome.</i></p>
							<a class="hana_promo_learn_more address_ajax" href="/hana-experiences">Explore Sea Ranch Cottages</a>
						</div>
					</div>
					<div class="hana_home_promo_right">
						<img src="/images/site/hana-GV-path.jpg" alt="Garden Suites & Condos" />
						<div class="hana_promo_content">
							<h2 class="landing_page">Garden Suites &amp; Condos</h2>
							<p>Staying for a night, weekend or want your family to experience the pristine, unspoiled beauty of the Hawai'i of your dreams? Then see where this path takes you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
							<a class="hana_promo_learn_more address_ajax" href="/hana-garden-view-suites-overview">Explore Garden Suites &amp; Condos</a>
						</div>
					</div>
					<div class="clear"></div>
					]]></copy>
				
					<thumbImg></thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-main.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
					<pdf_downloads>
						<pdf>
							<title></title>
							<url></url>
						</pdf>
						<pdf>
							<title></title>
							<url></url>
						</pdf>
					</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="0"  secondaryNav="true" id="1" position="1"  sitemapId="4.0.1" sitemapTitle="HĀNAS">
					<title>Hāna, Maui</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hawaii-youve-always-dreamed-of</slug>
						<pageTitle>The Hawai'i you've always dreamed of.</pageTitle>
						<description>Hāna Maui is the real Hawai’i. Authentic, relaxed, gracious &#8212; a place that’s truly paradise on earth.</description>
						<keywords> travaasa, Hāna, hana, rainforest, journey, aina, kai, experience, authentic, mana. </keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hāna, Maui: The Hawai’i you’ve always dreamed of.</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Hāna Maui is that kind of Hawai&rsquo;i. The real Hawai&rsquo;i. Authentic, relaxed, gracious &#8212; a place that&rsquo;s truly paradise on earth. A place where Hawaiian culture is as important as breathing. After your arrival from the Hāna Highway, your journey will continue in this place of <em>mana</em> (a powerful energy source).</p>
					<p>This is a place where <em>&lsquo;</em><em>Āina</em> (land) and <em>Kai</em> (ocean) are the foundation of life. A place where earth and water influence all daily activities. From treating the eye and soul to a feast of magnificent beauty that never ceases to delight, to actual sustenance through a bounty of food from the land and ocean. Beyond that, you&rsquo;ll discover that Hāna is passionately alive with the elements of ginger-scented breezes, lush rainforest, a place where <em>uwe ka lani ola ka honua</em> (rain as a source of life) promotes growth and abundance. It is the outward expression of Travaasa&rsquo;s core beliefs of change, experience, life force. Hāna simply has to be experienced to be believed.</p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-experiences">Explore Sea Ranch Cottages</a></p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-garden-view-suites-overview">Explore Garden Suites &amp; Condos</a></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-about-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Hāna, Maui</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-about.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
		
				<page section="4" primarySection="0"  secondaryNav="true" id="2" position="1"  sitemapId="4.0.2" sitemapTitle="JOURNEY TO TRAVAASA HĀNA">
					<title>The Road to Hāna</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>journey-to-travaasa-hana</slug>
						<pageTitle>The Road to Hāna</pageTitle>
						<description>Hāna has always been about the journey. Whether you are traveling thousands of miles or 52 on the Hāna Highway, you’ve made a commitment to discovering the unknown and learning from the trip..</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, journey, travel, pacific, maui, hāna   highway, kahului, paradise, trip, Kahului, Haleakala, rainforest, lilima.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>The first settlers traveled over 3,000 miles by canoe to get here. May we suggest the 52 miles it takes on the world famous Road to Hāna?</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Imagine what those first Polynesians saw when they reached Maui and landed on the shores of Kapeuokahi (Hāna&nbsp; Bay) 1,300 years ago. Well, we have a pretty good idea. They saw an immense volcano rising toward the sky, which they named <em>Haleakalā</em> (House of the Sun). They saw a rainforest canopied in mist. A wonderland of greens surrounded by cerulean sky and sea. And for contrast, this panoply of chartreuse, loden and moss was touched by the charcoal black of volcanic earth and punctuated by bright orange lilima blossoms. Not very different from what you see today in this most unspoiled paradise in the middle of the Pacific.</p>
					<p>For the first travelers to Hāna, their road was the ocean. Over 3,000 miles of open sea, a journey to the most remote and isolated archipelago in the world. For travelers to Hāna on the famous highway, your road is one of the top ten most beautiful drives in the U.S. <strong></strong></p>
					<p>For travelers of the self, your Hāna Travaasa starts in Kahului and continues on long after you reach Hāna.</p>
					<p><strong>Hāna has always been about the journey.</strong> Whether you are traveling thousands of miles or 52 on the Hāna Highway, you&rsquo;ve made a commitment to discovering the unknown and learning from the trip. Just like Travaasa. Our vision has always been to uncover the magic of travel, the story of the journey. &ldquo;Place&rdquo; matters to Travaasa. And Hāna is a stunning backdrop for a fascinating tale. Yours.</p>
					<p><em>&lsquo;</em>ō<em>lelo No&rsquo;eau &lsquo;Au I ke kai loa: </em>Swims the distant seas&mdash;said of one who travels afar. [Hawaiian Proverb]</p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-experiences">Explore Sea Ranch Cottages</a></p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-garden-view-suites-overview">Explore Garden Suites &amp; Condos</a></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-journey-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>The Journey</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-journey.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="0"  secondaryNav="true" id="3" position="1" sitemapId="4.0.3" sitemapTitle="HĀNA HOSPITALITY">
					<title>Hāna Hospitality</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-hospitality</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hāna Hospitality</pageTitle>
						<description>Hospitality is a Hawaiian way of life.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, talking story, Pog, hospitality, Hawaiian, family, oHāna.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Ho&lsquo;okipa (hospitality). It&rsquo;s a Hawaiian way of life.]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[
					<p>We are <em>&lsquo;Ohāna</em>. Family.</p>
					<p>The minute you arrive at Travaasa Hāna, you sense that you have been invited into someone&rsquo;s home. You receive a warm, casual, heartfelt greeting at our outdoor reception area.</p>
					<p>You&rsquo;ll be given a cool towel scented with lemon water to refresh you after your journey, and a traditional glass of <em>Pog</em> (guava, passionfruit and orange juice). This is genuine Hawaiian hospitality. A graciousness of times gone by. It&rsquo;s not scripted; it&rsquo;s natural. There is no training for this kind of hospitality. It is something every one of our team members, our <em>&lsquo;Ohāna</em> (family), grew up with.</p>
					<p>Our hospitality comes from living the Hawaiian lifestyle. And it shows. In fact, some of our repeat guests are charmed when they get invited to a family event at one our team member&rsquo;s homes. Our hospitality extends to everyday life. It doesn&rsquo;t stop after an eight-hour shift.</p>
					<p>This is the kind of genuine hospitality that can only come out of a place where there&rsquo;s no stoplight, no stop sign, no road rage and everyone waves to each other on the road with a truly natural smile. Why be in a rush, we ask? You are not rushed off to your room. You are not rushed off anywhere. There&rsquo;s no pressure here, which is why you won&rsquo;t find any clocks, TVs or radios in your room. We want you to stop and pass the time away in the Hawaiian tradition of &ldquo;talk story.&rdquo; We want to hear <em>your</em> story.</p>
					<p>It&rsquo;s something every single one of our team members grew up with.</p>
					<p>For Travaasa Hāna, it&rsquo;s a tradition of hospitality, spanning over 60 years.&nbsp;</p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-experiences">Explore Sea Ranch Cottages</a></p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-garden-view-suites-overview">Explore Garden Suites &amp; Condos</a></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-hospitality-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Hāna Hospitality</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-hospitality.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="6" primarySection="0"  secondaryNav="true" id="4" position="1" sitemapId="4.0.4" sitemapTitle="HĀNA HISTORY">
					<title>Hāna History</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-history</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hāna History</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa mechanical bull riding workout focuses on the engagement of core abdominal, back and thigh muscles.</description>
						<keywords>mechanical bull riding, core, abdominal, back and thigh muscles, Travaasa, balance</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hāna History</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>What started out as a &ldquo;retirement project&rdquo; evolved into the world-class destination that only a privileged few ever get to experience. But what really helped put Hāna on the map (besides its unparalleled beauty) was a baseball team.</p>
					<p>The story begins just after the Second World War with Paul Fagan, an entrepreneur from San Francisco. He had investments in the area and wanted to retire here. However, jobs were scarce for the residents and the town&rsquo;s survival was seriously in doubt. Paul believed Hāna held tremendous potential as a tourist destination. Together with his wife Helene, they designed a hotel for first-class travelers. This was an age when there was no such thing as a cut-rate tour, so luxury was the order of the day. In October 1946, the Ka&rsquo;uiki Inn opened. Hawaiian press accounts hailed it as &ldquo;the glamorous new resort on the Hāna Coast.&rdquo; Paul knew he had to get the word out to the mainland. Being a majority owner of the Pacific Coast League&rsquo;s San Francisco Seals, he knew the team needed a location for Spring Training in 1947. Since his team had just won the PCL Championship and set an attendance record, he &ldquo;awarded&rdquo; them with a trip to Hāna. The team also brought along a cadre of sportswriters who wrote glowing reports about the Inn and the area. One writer even coined the nickname still used today &ldquo;Heavenly Hāna.&rdquo; Their stories helped put Hāna and the Inn on the map. The Inn eventually evolved into the Hotel Hāna-Maui. Small and quietly isolated, Hāna quickly became a world-class destination for travelers and celebrities looking to get away from it all. And while the hotel has expanded and changed hands several times over the decades, one principle will always guide us at Travaasa Hāna. To keep &ldquo;Heavenly Hāna&rdquo; Maui&rsquo;s truly last Hawaiian place.</p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-experiences">Explore Sea Ranch Cottages</a></p>
					<p><a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-garden-view-suites-overview">Explore Garden Suites &amp; Condos</a></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-history-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>History</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-history.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<!--<page section="5" primarySection="0" secondaryNav="true" id="5" position="3" sitemapId="4.1" sitemapTitle="SEA RANCH COTTAGES OVERVIEW">
					<title>Sea Ranch Accommodations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>sea-ranch-cottages-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Sea Ranch Cottages Overview</pageTitle>
						<description>The Total Travaasa Package offers an all-inclusive stay along with ocean views.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Sea Ranch Cottage, Honua Spa, adventures, lanai, Pacific, Wellness Classes, Hamoa Beach, breakfast, lunch, dinner, Makana Activities Center, all inclusive.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Sea Ranch Cottages Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>The Total Travaasa Packages at our Sea Ranch Cottages are all-inclusive, and will leave you wanting for nothing. Awe-inspiring views that take your breath away, spa treatments to soothe and energize, experiences that satisfy your thirst for adventure, cuisine that satisfies the soul &ndash; it&rsquo;s all here to help you refresh, recharge and reconnect.</p>
					<p><em>Our Sea Ranch Cottages are reserved for adults and children 16 and over.</em></p>
					<ul>
						<li>Full breakfast, lunch, dinner and snacks at the pool bar each day; unlimited non-alcoholic beverages.</li>
						<li>Daily spa treatment or an off-property activity or tour.</li>
						<li>Numerous classes from our Five Pillars of experiences: Adventure, Culture, Culinary, Fitness and Spa/Wellness &ndash; select from Yoga, Barre, Outdoor Circuit, nutrition&nbsp; offerings and <span style="text-decoration: underline;">many more</span>. <strong>[Link to 4.1.1]</strong></li>
						<li>Makana Activities Center offerings &ndash; Choose from bicycle adventures, horseback riding, walking tours, stand up paddle board, &lsquo;ukulele lessons, net throwing and much, much more.</li>
						<li>Unlimited use of The Spa at Travaasa&rsquo;s steam room, cold plunge, hot tub &amp; fitness center.</li>
						<li>Daily use of sports equipment &ndash; Snorkel gear, bicycles, tennis rackets.</li>
						<li>In-room welcome basket with fresh local fruit &amp; snacks.</li>
						<li>Complimentary valet parking and Hamoa Beach shuttle.</li>
						<li>Complimentary transfer from and to Hāna airport.</li>
					</ul>
					<p><em>* If you&rsquo;re not looking for an all-inclusive experience, check out our Garden View Suites stay option.</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-overview-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Total Travaasa Package</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-overview.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				-->
				<!--<page section="6" primarySection="0" secondaryNav="true" id="6" position="3" sitemapId="4.2" sitemapTitle="Garden View Overview DUPLICATE">
					<title>Garden View Accommodations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-suites-overviews</slug>
						<pageTitle>Garden View Suites Overview</pageTitle>
						<description>Our Garden View options offer an experience that’s truly Travaasa, with an a la carte flexibility that’s perfect for tailoring the journey just for you.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, getaway, family vacation, garden view</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Garden View Suites Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Our Garden View stay options are a wonderful way to experience all the beauty of Hāna and have access to the rich amenities and services offered at Travaasa. A welcoming environment for children and families, the Garden View suites are also an attractive option for those staying elsewhere in Maui who just want to experience Hāna and explore local beaches and parks.</p>
					<p>Guests of our Garden View suites have access to our dining and spa services on an &agrave; la carte basis, and guests age 16 and older can access programs and activities on the Sea Ranch side of the property.</p>
					<p>Here is what your Garden View stay includes: </p>
					<ul>
					<li>Makana Activities Center offerings &ndash; Choose from bicycle adventures, horseback riding, walking tours, stand up paddle board, &lsquo;ukulele lessons, net throwing and much, much more.</li>
					<li>Daily use of sports equipment &ndash; snorkel gear, bicycles, tennis rackets.</li>
					<li>Enjoyment of the Garden Pool.</li>
					<li>Unlimited access to the fitness room.</li>
					</ul>
					<p><em>* If you&rsquo;re looking for an all-inclusive experience, please take a look at our <a href="#">Sea Ranch</a> stay options</em>.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-overview-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Garden View Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-overview.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				-->
				<page section="0" primarySection="1" root="true" secondaryNav="true" id="5" position="3" sitemapId="4.1" sitemapTitle="SEA RANCH COTTAGES OVERVIEW">
					<title>Sea Ranch Cottages</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-sea-ranch-cottages-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Sea Ranch Cottages Overview</pageTitle>
						<description>The Total Travaasa Package offers an all-inclusive stay along with ocean views.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Sea Ranch Cottage, Honua Spa, adventures, lanai, Pacific, Wellness Classes, Hamoa Beach, breakfast, lunch, dinner, Makana Activities Center, all inclusive.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Sea Ranch Cottages Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>The Total Travaasa Packages at our Sea Ranch Cottages are all-inclusive, and will leave you wanting for nothing. Awe-inspiring views that take your breath away, spa treatments to soothe and energize, experiences that satisfy your thirst for adventure, cuisine that satisfies the soul &ndash; it&rsquo;s all here to help you refresh, recharge and reconnect.</p>
					<p><em>Our Sea Ranch Cottages are reserved for adults and children 16 and over.</em></p>
					<ul>
						<li>Breakfast, lunch or dinner in our Ka&rsquo;uiki dining room or our caf&eacute;, Paniolo Lounge, plus snacks at the pool bar each day; unlimited non-alcoholic beverages.</li>
						<li>Daily spa treatment or an off-property activity or tour.</li>
						<li>Numerous classes from our Five Pillars of experiences: Adventure, Culture, Culinary, Fitness and Spa/Wellness &ndash; select from Yoga, Barre, Outdoor Circuit, nutrition&nbsp; offerings and <a href="/hana-experiences" class="address_ajax" >many more</a>. </li>
						<li>Makana Activities Center offerings &ndash; Choose from bicycle adventures, horseback riding, walking tours, stand up paddle board, &lsquo;ukulele lessons, net throwing and much, much more.</li>
						<li>Unlimited use of The Spa amenities, including steam room, cold plunge, hot tub &amp; fitness center.</li>
						<li>Daily use of sports equipment &ndash; Snorkel gear, bicycles, tennis rackets, and more.</li>
						<li>In&ndash;room welcome basket with fresh local fruit, snacks, Hana Blend coffee and our famous banana bread.</li>
						<li>Complimentary valet parking and Hamoa Beach shuttle.</li>
						<li>Complimentary transfer from and to Hāna airport.</li>
					</ul>
					<p><em>* If you&rsquo;re not looking for an all-inclusive experience, check out our <a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-garden-view-suites-overview">Garden View Suites</a> stay option.</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-overview-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Total Travaasa Package</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-overview.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<!--<page section="0" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="6" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.1" sitemapTitle="TRAVAASA HĀNA EXPERIENCES DUPLICATE">
					<title>Hāna Experiences</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-experiences</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hāna Experiences</pageTitle>
						<description>Enjoy Adventure, Culinary, Culture, Fitness and Spa and Wellness offerings at Travaasa Hāna.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Adventure, Culinary, Culture, Fitness and Spa and Wellness, journey, lei making, ukulele, hula, snorkeling, throw net fishing, hospitality, comforts, experiences, travaasas, ecology, culture, gardens, guides, ocean, pool.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hāna Experiences</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>While you are with us, you will enjoy our inimitable hospitality and beauty of place, and the comforts of everything you&rsquo;ve come to expect from a Travaasa experience: our healing and pampering spa, authentic Hawaiian pursuits (lei making, &lsquo;ukulele, hula, snorkeling, throw net fishing, opening a coconut, enjoying local gardens and guides who will share their knowledge of ecology and culture with you), a pool with an ocean view unlike any other, outdoor yoga, so you can experience all of life&mdash;while here, we&rsquo;re taking you on a further journey to self, to recognition, to life, to the real Hawai&rsquo;i.</p>
					<p>And one way to do this is through our diverse course offerings we call &ldquo;Travaasas.&rdquo; We offer five different pathways for you to explore: Adventure, Culinary, Culture, Fitness and Spa &amp; Wellness. You won&rsquo;t have any trouble finding something unique.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-experiences-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Travaasa Hāna Experiences</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-experiences.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="0" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="7" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.2" sitemapTitle="The Spa at Travaasa Hāna DUPLICATE">
					<title>Sea Ranch Overview</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-the-spa-at-travaasa-hana</slug>
						<pageTitle>The Spa at Travaasa Hana</pageTitle>
						<description>A range of transformative therapeutic experiences utilizing Hāna’s natural resources pampers and prepares you as your escape begins with a journey back to center.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, therapeutic, tranquility, health, balance, wellness, spirit</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to The Spa at Travaasa Hāna, a deeply relaxing sanctuary of peace and tranquility enhanced by Hāna&rsquo;s natural tropical beauty. We believe true health and balance come from the gifts of the earth and elements of nature, and that Hāna is a place of innate nurturing and well-being.</p>
					<p>At The Spa at Travaasa Hāna, we gratefully utilize the incredible bounty of Hāna, using its abundant plants, minerals and water to blend in our teas and create natural body and face products and treatments. The wide variety of therapeutic services we offer prepares our guests to experience Hāna more fully, thus restoring feelings of balance and wellness to body, mind, spirit and emotion</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="0" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="8" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.3" sitemapTitle="Dining DUPLICATE">
					<title>Dining</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-dining-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Dining</pageTitle>
						<description>At Travaasa you’ll find organic, locally-sourced produce, meat, fish and dairy.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Hawaiian, Asian, Polynesian, health-conscious, vegetarian, vegan, nourish.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Dining Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Nourishment</h2>
					<p>With the incredible abundance and inspiration of Hāna to draw from, our Executive Chef has created a dining experience that&rsquo;s pure Travaasa &ndash; a celebration of life and the bounty of the earth that nourishes us body and soul. He&rsquo;s coined a name for his eclectic, creative culinary style: Hāna Fusion, a combination of techniques from classical to innovative blending bold flavors with a focus on in-season, local ingredients.</p>
					<p>The menu incorporates many diverse layers of culinary influence central to Hawaiian culture. Alongside signature local dishes, you&rsquo;ll find elements of Asian and Old World European cuisine. Here at Travaasa Hāna, it all gets mixed up in a delicious m&eacute;lange as our chef creates familiar yet unique dishes with a Polynesian flair. And in keeping with the health-conscious ethos of the Hawaiian people, we also offer an extensive selection of gourmet vegetarian and vegan foods. Everything we serve is made from scratch with health and balance in mind.</p>
					<p>During your stay you can expect to savor a wide range of inventive, ambrosial dishes, such as our own Pohole Fern Shoot Salad, a native Hawaiian favorite. Fish wrapped in Ti Leaves. Seaweed salad. Taro. Fish smoked with guava and mango wood. Lilikoi Mahi with Hawaiian sweet potato and ginger lime coconut sauce. And an Open-faced Smoked Chicken Salad Sandwich on house-made bread with a locally grown sprout salad.</p>
					<p>Travaasa is all about the experience, a reminder that life is for living, and living well, and we always want you to leave happy. Dine with us and that philosophy is clear with every bite. </p>
					<h2>Eating Well</h2>
					<p>The Islands are a land rich with nature&rsquo;s bounty. And we only select fresh, organic, locally-sourced produce, fish, meat and dairy. Premium foods that are in-season and in our area to bring you only the finest sustainable breakfast, lunch and dinner options. At Travaasa Hāna we like to nourish, not only the spirit, but also the body. Because good food means good health.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-dining-overview-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Dining Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-dining-overview.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="0" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="9" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.4" sitemapTitle="Accommodations: Sea Ranch Cottages DUPLICATE">
					<title>Accommodations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-accommodations-sea-ranch-cottages</slug>
						<pageTitle>Accommodations: Sea Ranch Cottages</pageTitle>
						<description>Sea Ranch Cottages offer an all-inclusive stay along with ocean views.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Sea Ranch Cottage, Honua Spa, adventures, lanai, Pacific, Wellness Classes, Hamoa Beach, breakfast, lunch, dinner, Makana Activities Center, all inclusive.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Accommodations: Sea Ranch Cottages</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>The awe-inspiring views of the Hāna Coastline from a Sea Ranch Cottage will take your breath away. All cottages have sweeping views of the Pacific. So we understand why you may never leave the lanai (porch). Your cottage is a haven.&nbsp; Reflecting the culture of &ldquo;Old Hawai&rsquo;i&rdquo;, the cottage&rsquo;s serenity makes it the ideal place to recharge and reconnect with each other. However, our world class spa awaits to pamper your body and soul. Adventures abound on and off the property. And local, fresh cuisine awaits.</p><p><em>Our Sea Ranch Cottages are reserved for adults and children 16 and over. Families and children are welcome in our Garden View Suites.  Thank you.</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-accomodations-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Sea Ranch Cottages</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-accomodations.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="0" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="10" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.5" sitemapTitle="Rates and Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages DUPLICATE">
					<title><![CDATA[Rates & Packages]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-rates-and-packages-sea-ranch-cottages</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages]]></pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa barre exercises lengthen, strengthen and create lean dancer muscles.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, barre, exercises, Hawaiian, high-energy, fitness, ballet, sculpts, muscles, dancers.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Total Travaasa</h2>
					<p> When you treat yourself to the Total Travaasa package in Hāna, you won&rsquo;t have to worry about a thing. In addition to accommodations at our Sea Ranch Cottages, all meals, snacks and non alcoholic beverages are included, as well as your choice of any 60 minute treatment from our award winning spa. Also included are all on-property activities as well as off property activities such as a coastal horseback ride. Or for really adventurous souls, try stand up paddling (Hoe he&rsquo;e nalu).</p>
					<p> <strong>Rates begin at $770 per couple</strong> (tax and service not included)</p>
                    <p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<h2>Sunrise &amp; Spa Package</h2>
					<p>The Hāna Sunrise &amp; Spa package includes accommodations in one of our Sea Ranch Cottages, a generous and healthy breakfast, access to many of the activities including daily Yoga, and a 60 minute spa treatment of your choice.</p>
					<p><strong>Rates begin at $625 per couple</strong> (tax and service not included)</p>
					<p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<h2>Travaasa Hāna Sunrise Package</h2>
					<p>Experience Travaasa Hāna and find out why so many people have chosen to discover the &ldquo;real Hawai&rsquo;i&rdquo; here and all we have to offer. Included with your accommodations in one of our Sea Ranch Cottages is a generous breakfast and access to many of the cultural activities featured throughout the property.</p>
					<p><strong>Rates begin at $495 per couple</strong> (tax and service not included)</p>
					<p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<p><em>Please note that all guests on the Sea Ranch Cottage side of the property must be 16 years or older (except during our Family Weeks).</em></p>
					<p><em>If you&rsquo;re not looking for an all-inclusive experience, check out our <a href="#">Garden View</a> stay options.</em> [LINK TO: 4.2]</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-rates-packages-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-rates-packages.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="0" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="11" position="6" sitemapId="4.1.6" sitemapTitle="Off-Property Excursions DUPLICATE">
					<title>Off-Property Excursions</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-off-property-excursions</slug>
						<pageTitle>Off-Property Excursions</pageTitle>
						<description>Off-property excursions let you get to know Hāna and Maui.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, black-sand beach, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, swimming, horseback riding, cultural center, ancestors, Hāna Bay, Maui Stables, Ono Organic Farms, Wai Anapanapa State Park, off-property, excursions, Hāna Cultural Center, Kahanu Garden, ‘Ōhe’o Gulch at Haleakalā National Park, Seven Pools, Waimoku Falls</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Off-Property Excursions</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Hāna Town Center</h2>
					<p>Get a glimpse of community life by taking a stroll through the Town Center and browse the shops. The bank, post office, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, florist, Hāna Ranch Store and several gift shops are located here. Town Center is just a five-minute walk from the hotel.</p>
					<h2>Wai&rsquo;ānapanapa State Park</h2>
					<p>Walk along the ancient &ldquo;King&rsquo;s Trail,&rdquo; explore a legendary freshwater cave, discover important archeological sites, visit Maui&rsquo;s only black-sand beach and of course, it all overlooks the Pacific Ocean.</p>
					<h2>Hāna Bay</h2>
					<p><em>Kapueokahi</em> (the lone owl) is commonly referred to as &ldquo;Hāna Bay.&rdquo; It was the major shipping port for the sugar companies. Today, this quarter-mile slice of black and white sand is a favorite with local families for swimming, snorkeling and strolling. Complimentary snorkeling equipment is available at the Concierge Desk.</p>
					<h2>Hāna Cultural Center</h2>
					<p>Just a short walk from Travaasa Hāna, the Cultural Center houses a fascinating collection of historical photos, documents and artifacts. The gift shop helps support the collections and any donation is greatly appreciated.</p>
					<p>Open Monday &ndash; Friday 10:00 a.m.&ndash;4:00 pm.</p>
					<h2>Kahanu Garden</h2>
					<p>The Garden is home to some of Hawai&rsquo;i&rsquo;s most precious treasures. <em>Pi&rsquo;ilanihale</em>, a <em>heiau</em> or temple, is believed to be the largest man-made, pre-Western structure in all of Polynesia. Self-guided tours are offered Monday&ndash;Friday 10:00 a.m.&ndash;2:00 p.m. by the National Tropical Botanical Gardens. Guided tours are available on Saturdays by appointment. Advance reservations are required.</p>
					<h2>&lsquo;Ōhe&rsquo;o Gulch at Haleakalā National Park</h2>
					<p>The Park features the famous &ldquo;Pools of &#332;heo&rdquo; &ndash; a series of cascading pools leading to the ocean. The Waimoku Falls Trail is a five-mile round trip hike that takes you through a bamboo forest to the 400-foot Waimoku Falls. NOTE: The Park is approximately 11 miles from Hāna town and we urge you to drive there with caution and heed all caution signs while at the park.</p>
					<h2>ONO Organic Farms</h2>
					<p>This family-owned farm where everything is hand picked and certified organic is aptly named. ONO is the Hawaiian word for delicious. You&rsquo;ll tour this pure organic paradise and enjoy a tropical fruit tasting adventure by sampling 12 varieties of tropical fruit and ONO-grown coffee.</p>
					<h2>Maui Stables</h2>
					<p>Go on a historical and cultural horseback ride through the ancient unspoiled landscape of Maui. This isn&rsquo;t your typical stable. Maui Stables is native owned and operated. The <em>Alaka&rsquo;i</em> (guides) and <em>Kako&rsquo;o</em> (apprentice) who accompany you can trace their family roots back hundreds of years. Each tour will begin with a <em>pule</em> (prayer) and <em>oli</em>, or call to our ancestors. Throughout the ride they&rsquo;ll share stories of their ancestors and the land.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-off-property-excursions-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Off-Property Excursions</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-off-property-excursions.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				-->
				<page section="1" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="true" id="12" position="0" sitemapId="4.1.1" sitemapTitle="TRAVAASA HĀNA EXPERIENCES">
					<title>Hāna Experiences</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-experiences</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hāna Experiences</pageTitle>
						<description>Enjoy Adventure, Culinary, Culture, Fitness and Spa and Wellness offerings at Travaasa Hāna.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Adventure, Culinary, Culture, Fitness and Spa and Wellness, journey, lei making, ukulele, hula, snorkeling, throw net fishing, hospitality, comforts, experiences, travaasas, ecology, culture, gardens, guides, ocean, pool.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hāna Experiences</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>There are countless things to do here. Picking up your jaw from the ground is one of them.</p><p>While you are with us, you will enjoy our inimitable hospitality and beauty of place, and the comforts of everything you&rsquo;ve come to expect from a Travaasa experience: our healing and pampering spa, authentic Hawaiian pursuits (lei making, &lsquo;ukulele, hula, snorkeling, throw net fishing, opening a coconut, enjoying local gardens and guides who will share their knowledge of ecology and culture with you), a pool with an ocean view unlike any other, outdoor yoga, so you can experience all of life&mdash;while here, we&rsquo;re taking you on a further journey to self, to recognition, to life, to the real Hawai&rsquo;i.</p>
					<p>And one way to do this is through our diverse course offerings we call &ldquo;Travaasas.&rdquo; We offer five different pathways for you to explore: Adventure, Culinary, Culture, Fitness and Spa &amp; Wellness. You won&rsquo;t have any trouble finding something unique.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-experiences-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Travaasa Hāna Experiences</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-experiences.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="1" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="13" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.1.1" sitemapTitle="Adventure DUPLICATE">
					<title>Adventure</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-adventure-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Adventure</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa adventure offerings thrill and delight.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, outdoors, adventure, outside world, magic, journey, play.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Adventure Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Travel is an adventure, and it’s only fitting, since Travaasa is all about the magic of the journey, that our Adventure offerings are designed to thrill and delight. (It doesn’t hurt that they take place in drop-dead gorgeous Hāna, either.) Travaasa celebrates the great outdoors with adventurous and stimulating play that removes the tether from technology and brings back the simple pleasures of reconnecting with the outside world.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-adventure-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Adventure Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-adventure.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="1" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="14" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.1.2" sitemapTitle="Culinary DUPLICATE">
					<title>Culinary</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-culinary-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Culinary</pageTitle>
						<description>Hawai’i is known for fresh, glorious produce, fish and more, and Hāna is no exception with locally sourced, organic fruits, vegetables, seafood and meat that’s the best quality.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, seafood, meat, vegetables, culinary, Maui, skills, local produce, pineapple, coconut.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Culinary Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Hawai&rsquo;i is known for fresh, glorious produce, fish and more, and Hāna is no exception. We serve locally sourced, organic fruits, vegetables, seafood and meat that&rsquo;s the best quality. Many Hawaiians say that you could get lost in Maui and never starve because of the abundance of food, ripe for the picking, all around you, and it&rsquo;s true. Our Culinary programs offer everything from basic culinary skills to learning how to make best use of local produce (how do you husk a coconut, and what is the proper way to slice a pineapple?) We&rsquo;ll show you all of that and much more. Sample for yourself some of our scintillating selections.&nbsp;</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-culinary-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Culinary Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-culinary.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="1" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="15" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.1.3" sitemapTitle="Culture DUPLICATE">
					<title>Culture</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-culture-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Culture</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa culture classes focus on creative expression, nature, conversation, music, dance and storytelling.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, ukulele, song, story, Hawaiian, skills, hula, mele.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Culture Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>This is your time to explore the world so you can come home richer for having learned new skills, heard other&rsquo;s stories and immersed yourself in creative outlets that let your soul soar. This is your time to learn how to Travaasa, and there&rsquo;s no place more rewarding to do this than Travaasa Hāna where you&rsquo;ll discover that every hula and every <em>&lsquo;ukulele</em> song tell a story. In Hawaiian it&rsquo;s called <em>mele</em> (song story), and you&rsquo;ll be able to create your own <em>mele</em> weaving together what makes your Hāna so special, and what makes your Travaasa stay special in a unique, Hāna way.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-culture-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Culture Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-culture.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="1" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="16" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.1.4" sitemapTitle="Fitness DUPLICATE">
					<title>Fitness</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-fitness-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Fitness</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa fitness focuses on balance, core work and flexibility</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, fitness, toning, strengthening, body, classes, sessions, yoga, Wellness Pavillion, Banyan Tree, core work.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Fitness Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Strengthening and toning the body is a natural activity at Travaasa Hāna, and we offer a wide range of classes, sessions and everyday events to leave you feeling like a new person. And it just so happens, you&rsquo;ll have a beautiful environment to work out in, whether it&rsquo;s in our open-air yoga area under a gracious Banyan Tree, our serene &ldquo;all-doors-open-to-the-breezes&rdquo; Wellness Pavilion, or out on the wild Hāna coast.</p>
					<p>Our fitness Travaasas focus on balance, core work and flexibility. With this well-rounded selection, we&rsquo;re not promising miracles, but we just bet you&rsquo;ll leave here feeling better and stronger.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-fitness-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Fitness Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-fitness.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="1" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="17" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.1.5" sitemapTitle="Spa and Wellness DUPLICATE">
					<title><![CDATA[Spa & Wellness]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-spa-and-wellness</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Spa & Wellness]]></pageTitle>
						<description>Our spa and wellness offerings are designed for your inner and outer needs.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, wellness, inner, outer, balanced state of mind, healthy body, stretch, meditation, yoga, posture, breath work.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Spa & Wellness Overview]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Our spa &amp; wellness offerings are designed for your inner and outer needs. A balanced state of mind, coupled with a managed stress life, a healthy body and a satisfied soul, gives focus and a point of view to our lives. We achieve that through meditation, stretch, yoga, posture and breath work. Not to mention stimulating health-oriented consultations that will pique your curiosity. Think of these workshops as a wellness toolkit you&rsquo;ll be able to refer to again and again after you leave here.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-wellness-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Spa & Wellness Overview]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-wellness.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" parentId="1" secondaryNav="true" id="18" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.1.1" sitemapTitle="Adventure">
					<title>Adventure</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-adventure-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Adventure</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa adventure offerings thrill and delight.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, outdoors, adventure, outside world, magic, journey, play.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Adventure Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Travel is an adventure, and it’s only fitting, since Travaasa is all about the magic of the journey, that our Adventure offerings are designed to thrill and delight. (It doesn’t hurt that they take place in drop-dead gorgeous Hāna, either.) Travaasa celebrates the great outdoors with adventurous and stimulating play that removes the tether from technology and brings back the simple pleasures of reconnecting with the outside world.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-adventure-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Adventure Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-adventure.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="19" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.1.1.1" sitemapTitle="Equine">
					<title>Equine</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-equine</slug>
						<pageTitle>Equine</pageTitle>
						<description>Reconnect with your innate instinctual intelligence through working with horses.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, equine, experiences, horses, paniolo, alakai, cowboy, tour leader.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Equine</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Signature Experience</h2><p>A deep connection with nature and plants and animals is a Hawaiian tradition. At our stables, you’ll learn to lead and project your intentions as you are guided by our equine team. No previous horse experience needed for this Travaasa that will teach you how to establish communication with another being through respect, sensitivity and awareness.</p>
					<h2>Trail Rides</h2>
					<p>Hawaiian cowboys or <em>paniolo&rsquo;s</em> have ridden the remote and unspoiled slopes, plains and coastline for over 175 years. And there is nothing quite like enjoying the superb, natural beauty of Maui on Hāna&rsquo;s extensive trail system. You&rsquo;ll be accompanied by an <em>Alaka&rsquo;i</em>, or trained tour leader, who will share stories of the land and its people. No previous horse experience needed.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-equine-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Equine</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-equine.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="20" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.1.1.2" sitemapTitle="Walks">
					<title>Walks</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-walks</slug>
						<pageTitle>Walks</pageTitle>
						<description>Explore coastal walks that lets you experience native plants in this place of great beauty, or walk to Hamoa Beach.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Hamoa Beach, canoe plants, coastal walk, Jame Michener, Dr. Beach, foliage, waves, boogie boarding, ocean, Pele, Goddess of Fire, mo olelo, 'Ālau Island.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Coastal Walks</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Waipāuma Coastal Walk</h2><p>Start your morning with a coastal walk you&rsquo;ll remember for the rest of your life. Our guides will point out various native plants (as well as &ldquo;canoe plants,&rdquo; plants that were brought to Hawai&rsquo;i by the first Polynesians over 1,300 years ago to ensure their survival). You&rsquo;ll also see the picturesque &lsquo;Ālau Island, a bird sanctuary with an unbelievable grouping of wind-tossed palm trees at its summit. Many of our guides were raised in Hāna, and will share their own personal mo&lsquo;olelo (stories) of growing up in this place of great beauty.</p>
					<h2>Walk to Hamoa Beach</h2>
					<p><p>A three-mile walk from the hotel, Hamoa Beach is a broad curve of untouched sand described by the late Pulitzer Prize winner James Michener as &ldquo;The most perfect crescent beach in the Pacific.&rdquo; Sheltered by lush foliage on its western side, this is a not-to-be-missed beach with perfect waves for boogie boarding* and the trademark indigo Hawaiian ocean with patches of bright, vivid clear blue. The walk takes you past the famous Ka-iwi-o-Pele hill which is said to hold the bones of Pele, Goddess of Fire (and the Hawaiian Volcano Goddess), and broad ranchland with free-roaming cows and egrets. Spectacular views in every direction, with the end of your journey, Hamoa Beach, being a real showstopper.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-walks-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Walks</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-walks.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="21" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.1.1.3" sitemapTitle="Stand Up Paddling">
					<title>Stand Up Paddling</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-stand-up-paddling</slug>
						<pageTitle>Stand Up Paddling</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa adventure offerings thrill and delight.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, outdoors, adventure, outside world, magic, journey, play.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Stand Up Paddling</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p><em>Hoe he&rsquo;e nalu</em>, or Stand Up Paddling (SUP) has a rich Hawaiian heritage that is re-emerging as a popular water sport around the world. It is very popular with cross-athletes and provides a strong core workout, promotes balance and general fitness. Not to mention that it&rsquo;s a fun way to view the beautiful natural surroundings of Hāna Bay.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-stand-up-paddling-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Stand Up Paddling</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-stand-up-paddling.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<!--
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="22" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.1.1.4" sitemapTitle="Outrigger Canoe Paddling">
					<title>Outrigger Canoe Paddling</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-outrigger-canoe-paddling</slug>
						<pageTitle>Outrigger Canoe Paddling</pageTitle>
						<description>Outrigger Canoe Paddling in Hāna Bay is a sport you’ll thrill to.</description>
						<keywords> travaasa, Hāna, hana, craft, clubs, outrigger canoe, islands, Hāna Bay, Hāna Canoe Club.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Outrigger Canoe Paddling</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>These amazing craft have evolved over thousands of years and are still a common site around the islands thanks to the many clubs where teams race for pride and prestige. Now, your experienced steersman from the Hāna Canoe Club won&rsquo;t expect you to set any speed records, but he&rsquo;ll make sure you experience the thrill of outrigger canoeing in Kapueokahi, or Hāna Bay.</p>
					<p><strong>Coming to Travaasa Hāna in September 2011!</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-outrigger-canoe-paddling-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Outrigger Canoe Paddling</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-outrigger-canoe-paddling.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				-->
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="23" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.1.1.5" sitemapTitle="Snorkeling">
					<title>Snorkeling</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-snorkeling</slug>
						<pageTitle>Snorkeling</pageTitle>
						<description>Maui is a snorkeler’s paradise and Hāna Bay holds some of the island’s best coral heads.</description>
						<keywords> travaasa, Hāna, hana, snorkeling, Maui, Hāna Bay, sea sports, adventure, tropical fish</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Snorkeling</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Maui is by far the most popular snorkeling island in Hawai&rsquo;i. You&rsquo;ll snorkel off the beach of <em>Kapueokahi</em>, or Hāna Bay in a protected cove teeming with tropical fish and living coral gardens in amazing shapes and colors. Enjoy this snorkeler&rsquo;s paradise, and after your first glimpse of what lies beneath the ocean&rsquo;s surface, you might just become hooked on this breathtaking experience.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-snorkeling-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Snorkeling</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-snorkeling.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="24" position="6" sitemapId="4.1.1.1.6" sitemapTitle="Archery">
					<title>Archery</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-archery</slug>
						<pageTitle>Archery</pageTitle>
						<description>Archery boosts mental and physical health and fitness, and is especially memorable when practiced at Travaasa Hāna.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, archery, focus, patience, attention skills.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Archery</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Learning archery outdoors at Travaasa Hāna is a conundrum. On one hand, you are discovering the foundation of archery&mdash;boosting your mental attention and connecting your breath to physical performance. On the other hand, the scenery around you is so beautiful, you might have a hard time concentrating. Which is exactly why, ultimately, this is the perfect place to practice focus techniques with so many scenic distractions around you. You&rsquo;ll develop your attention skills, patience, flexibility, concentration, and understand why great archers continually develop these simple concepts to heighten all aspects of their lives.</p>
					<p><strong>Coming to Travaasa Hāna in fall 2011!</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-archery-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Archery</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-archery.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="25" position="7" sitemapId="4.1.1.1.8" sitemapTitle="Challenge Course">
					<title>Challenge Course</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-challenge-course</slug>
						<pageTitle>Challenge Course</pageTitle>
						<description>Enjoy an empowering mission and tackle physical challenges that help you discover hidden strengths and break free of self-imposed limitations.</description>
						<keywords>ravaasa, Hāna, hana, Outward Bound, leap, balance, adventure, zipline.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Challenge Elements</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Travaasa, in partnership with Outward Bound Professional, is creating a challenge course designed to push you to the limits of your personal comfort zone (and beyond). It&rsquo;s at this edge you&rsquo;ll discover untapped reserves of strength and experience the sublime empowerment of overcoming what once seemed beyond you. We look forward to joining you on a thrilling adventure for both mind and body.</p>
					<p><strong>Coming to Travaasa Hāna in winter 2011-2012!</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-challenge-course-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Challenge Course</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-challenge-course.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" parentId="1" secondaryNav="true" id="26" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.1.2" sitemapTitle="Culinary">
					<title>Culinary</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-culinary-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Culinary</pageTitle>
						<description>Hawai’i is known for fresh, glorious produce, fish and more, and Hāna is no exception with locally sourced, organic fruits, vegetables, seafood and meat that’s the best quality.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, seafood, meat, vegetables, culinary, Maui, skills, local produce, pineapple, coconut.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Culinary Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Hawai&rsquo;i is known for fresh, glorious produce, fish and more, and Hāna is no exception. We serve locally sourced, organic fruits, vegetables, seafood and meat that&rsquo;s the best quality. Many Hawaiians say that you could get lost in Maui and never starve because of the abundance of food, ripe for the picking, all around you, and it&rsquo;s true. Our Culinary programs offer everything from basic culinary skills to learning how to make best use of local produce (how do you husk a coconut, and what is the proper way to slice a pineapple?) We&rsquo;ll show you all of that and much more. Sample for yourself some of our scintillating selections.&nbsp;</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-culinary-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Culinary Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-culinary.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="27" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.1" sitemapTitle="Basic Culinary Skills">
					<title>Basic Culinary Skills</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-basic-culinary-skills</slug>
						<pageTitle>Basic Culinary Skills</pageTitle>
						<description>Learn skills and techniques that can help transform you from casual cook to gourmet chef.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, culinary, basic culinary skills, culinary skills, culinary technique, culinary tips, gourmet, gourmet cuisine, cuisine, knife skills</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Basic Culinary Skills</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>This hands-on demonstration focuses on learning basic culinary skills and techniques you can use to create dishes that &ldquo;wow&rdquo; in your kitchen at home. Let our gourmet culinary team delight you with ways to prepare, cook and present cuisine you can share and savor with family and friends. On any given week we will explore one of the following areas: </p>
					<ol>
					<li>Eggs - everything you've always wanted to know about the multitalented egg</li>
					<li>Knife skills - tips, tricks and techniques</li>
					<li>Stocks and sauces.</li>
					</ol>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-basic-culinary-skills-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Basic Culinary Skills</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-basic-culinary-skills.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="28" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.2" sitemapTitle="Dinner Party 101">
					<title>Dinner Party 101</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-dinner-party-101</slug>
						<pageTitle>Dinner Party 101</pageTitle>
						<description>Get inspired for your next gathering with quick, unique recipes everyone will love.</description>
						<keywords> travaasa, Hāna, hana, entertaining, dinner party, potluck, party dish, party recipe, quick recipe, easy recipe</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Dinner Party 101</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Have guests coming over and don't know what to make? Headed to a party and want to bring something different than the same old standard dish you always bring? Join our culinary team and learn three quick and easy (but unique) dishes that will have your friends asking, "Where you'd get that recipe?"</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-easy-entertaining-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Easy Entertaining</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-easy-entertaining.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="29" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.3" sitemapTitle="Healthy Regional Cuisine">
					<title>Healthy Regional Cuisine</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-healthy-regional-cuisine</slug>
						<pageTitle>Healthy Regional Cuisine</pageTitle>
						<description>Discover the flavors that make Hawaii a paradise for creating delicious, healthy cuisine.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, hawaii, hawaiian cuisine, hawaiian flavors, fusion cuisine, fusion, gourmet, paradise, locally sourced</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Healthy Regional Cuisine</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Modern Hawaiian cuisine is a fusion of many diverse ethnic flavors brought to the islands by immigrants throughout the region’s rich history. The island is paradise for gourmets, with abundant fruits and vegetables grown from rich volcanic soil, a wide variety of high quality, fresh fish and locally sourced cattle. Here you'll learn about Hawaii's many food staples and try your hand at some of our most revered local dishes.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-healthy-regional-cuisine-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Healthy Regional Cuisine</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-healthy-regional-cusine.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="30" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.4" sitemapTitle="Juicing 2.0">
					<title>Juicing 2.0</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-juicing-2_0</slug>
						<pageTitle>Juicing 2.0</pageTitle>
						<description>Use whole foods to blend and mix fresh juices, soups, dips and more.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, dips, soups, juices, salsas, spreads, desserts, Hawai’i, juicing, fruits, vegetables, bounty.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Juicing 2.0</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>If ever there was a more ideal place to for you to try juicing, Hawai&rsquo;i is the place. The rich and varied bounty of fruits and vegetables lets you whip up a nearly endless list of creations. But this isn&rsquo;t &lsquo;old school&rsquo; blending filled with chopping, slopping and mopping here. This is Juicing 2.0 Hāna style. Together, we&rsquo;ll use whole foods to blend and mix fresh juices, soups, dips, spreads, desserts and salsas.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-juicing-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Juicing</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-juicing.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="31" position="6" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.5" sitemapTitle="Nourish Flourish">
					<title>Nourish Flourish</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-nourish-flourish</slug>
						<pageTitle>Nourish Flourish</pageTitle>
						<description>xxx</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, nourish, flourish, rejuvenation, enrichment, transformation, vitality, invigorating, healthy food, sprout, harvest, health, wellness, fitness.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Nourish Flourish</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Hawai&rsquo;i is the ultimate place on earth for fresh, bountiful food. And at Travaasa H?na, you can learn all the ways food nourishes us all so we can flourish&mdash;by eating well and eating fresh. This Travaasa helps you develop an awareness of the impact of our consumption, and the ramifications of the ecological production of what we eat. Across the spectrum of health, wellness and fitness, discover how food offers vital performance for everyone&mdash;discover how you can flourish from what you eat here in Hāna, and when you go back home.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-nourish-flourish-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Nourish Flourish</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-nourish-flourish.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="32" position="7" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.6" sitemapTitle="Fish Preparation">
					<title>Fish Preparation</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-fish-preparation</slug>
						<pageTitle>Fish Preparation</pageTitle>
						<description>Debunk the myths and discover everything you need to prepare and enjoy delicious fish dishes at home.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, fish, fish preparation, prepare fish, nutritious, culinary, cooking, demystify, ocean, tradition, experience, chef, recipe</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Fish Preparation</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Fish is nutritious and delicious, yet many people are reluctant to attempt preparing a fish course at home. This culinary experience will help demystify cooking with fish, giving you knowledge about how to select, buy, clean, store and prepare it. We&rsquo;ll honor the ocean&rsquo;s bounty through a range of simple and versatile techniques and explore the culinary heritage and fish traditions of Hawai’i.. You&rsquo;ll watch, experience, and taste as our Chef walks you through the preparation of three different fish recipes.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-fish-preparation-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Fish Preparation</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-fish-preparation.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="33" position="8" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.7" sitemapTitle="The Art of the Cocktail">
					<title>The Art of the Cocktail</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-the-art-of-the-cocktail</slug>
						<pageTitle>The Art of the Cocktail</pageTitle>
						<description>Go far beyond a shot and a beer to discover the depth of flavors and surging creativity that makes spirits sing and elevates mixology to art.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, hawaii, cocktail, mixology, lounge, bar, aperitif, specialty, after-dinner, sophistication, creativity, bartender, mai thai, martini, muddle</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>The Art of the Cocktail</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>We are in a mixology renaissance. More and more lounges, bars and restaurants are offering lists of aperitifs, specialty cocktails and after-dinner drinks that sparkle with sophistication and creativity. So the bartender&rsquo;s trick is how best to combine juices, purees, fruits, spices and wonderful fresh ingredients to develop seductive new offerings and reinvigorate the classics we all know and love. Find out why the Mai Thai is synonymous with Hawaii. (Or is it?) The difference between a martini shaken or stirred. Discover what a muddle is and why you would use it. Join us as we embark on a tasting journey, learning how quintessential old-world recipes have morphed in search of the complex, layered flavors that create today&rsquo;s savory new trends.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-art-of-cocktail-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>The Art of the Cocktail</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-art-cocktail.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="34" position="9" sitemapId="4.1.1.2.8" sitemapTitle="Tastings Series">
					<title>Tastings Series</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-tastings-series</slug>
						<pageTitle>Tastings Series</pageTitle>
						<description>Rotating sessions to educate your palette to the nuance of food and beverage.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, palette, educate, guava, coconut water, coconut milk, gourmet chocolate, locally grown, coffee, artisanal cheese, beer, tea flights.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Tastings Series</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>These rotating sessions will take you on a wonderful voyage of culinary discovery. On any given week you may be offered the opportunity to explore and enjoy the flavors of guava, coconut water (milk), gourmet chocolate, locally grown coffee, artisanal cheese, wine, beer, or tea flights.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-tastings-series-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Tastings Series</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-tastings-series.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" parentId="1" secondaryNav="true" id="35" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.1.3" sitemapTitle="Culture">
					<title>Culture</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-culture-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Culture</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa culture classes focus on creative expression, nature, conversation, music, dance and storytelling.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, ukulele, song, story, Hawaiian, skills, hula, mele.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Culture Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>This is your time to explore the world so you can come home richer for having learned new skills, heard other&rsquo;s stories and immersed yourself in creative outlets that let your soul soar. This is your time to learn how to Travaasa, and there&rsquo;s no place more rewarding to do this than Travaasa Hāna where you&rsquo;ll discover that every hula and every <em>&lsquo;ukulele</em> song tell a story. In Hawaiian it&rsquo;s called <em>mele</em> (song story), and you&rsquo;ll be able to create your own <em>mele</em> weaving together what makes your Hāna so special, and what makes your Travaasa stay special in a unique, Hāna way.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-culture-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Culture Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-culture.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="36" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.1" sitemapTitle="Hula">
					<title>Hula</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-hula</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hula</pageTitle>
						<description>Every hula tells a story and you’ll learn the hand and foot movements that go along with telling it.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, hula, story, cultural guides, teacher, childhood, generation, dance, traditions, aina, kai.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hula</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Every hula tells a story, and you&rsquo;ll learn all the graceful hand and foot movements that go along with telling it. Hula is more than just a dance&mdash;it is something that links Hawaiians to <em>&lsquo;Āina</em> (land) and <em>Kai</em> (ocean) and in broader terms, to the story of life. Hula is traditionally a way that stories and traditions were passed from generation to generation. Originally, hula was danced by men, but now it is performed by both men and women. You&rsquo;ll learn a story from one of our cultural guides, your <em>kumu</em> (teacher) who&rsquo;s been practicing hula since childhood.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-hula-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Hula</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-hula.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="37" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.2" sitemapTitle="Lei Making">
					<title>Lei Making</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-lei-making</slug>
						<pageTitle>Lei Making</pageTitle>
						<description>Leis are used to celebrate all occasions in Hawai’I, and you’ll learn lei-making techniques in our classes.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, lei, Plumeria, classes, techniques, blooms, Ti Leaf, Kukui Nut, lei wili, lei hili, lei kui pololei.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Lei Making</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>You were probably charmed by the <em>Ti</em> leaf <em>lei</em> adorned with Plumeria blooms you received upon arrival, or maybe you&rsquo;re still wearing the <em>Kukui</em> Nut <em>lei</em> we gave you. Learn how to make your own <em>Ti</em> leaf <em>lei</em>, or string Plumeria blooms for a colorful, wonderfully scented <em>lei</em>. <em>Leis</em> are traditionally used to celebrate all occasions in Hawai&rsquo;i, and we have a variety of classes where you can learn different techniques, from<em> lei wili</em> (twisting),<em> lei hili</em> (braiding),<em> lei kui pololei</em> (strung with a needle) and more.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-lei-making-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Lei Making</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-lei-making.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="38" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.3" sitemapTitle="Ukulele">
					<title>'Ukulele</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-ukulele</slug>
						<pageTitle>'Ukulele</pageTitle>
						<description>Learn how to play the 'ukulele.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, ukulele, Portuguese, 19th century, chords, song, lū‘au, luau, instrument, Noe Noe, gift shop.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>'Ukulele</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>First introduced to Hawaiians by the Portuguese in the 19th century, the &lsquo;Ukulele is now more well known as a Hawaiian instrument. You&rsquo;ll learn basic chords, and before long, you&rsquo;ll be playing a well-known song. We&rsquo;ll send you home with sheet music, a little bit of history about the &lsquo;Ukulele, and we even sell small &lsquo;Ukulele in our Noe Noe gift shop&mdash;just in case you want to serenade family and friends at your next lū&lsquo;au.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-ukulele-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>'Ukulele</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-ukulele.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="39" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.4" sitemapTitle="Hawaiian Throw Net">
					<title>Hawaiian "Throw Net"</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-hawaiian-throw-net</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hawaiian "Throw Net"</pageTitle>
						<description>Learn how to do traditional Hawaiian throw net in the hopes of catching a fish.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, throw net, Hawaiian, fish, generations, handmade, traveler, ocean, oHāna</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hawaiian "Throw Net"</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Hawaiian &ldquo;throw net&rdquo; has been passed on from generation to generation in Hawai&rsquo;i, and handmade nets are becoming family heirlooms (easy to see why when you see a handmade net and inspect the intricate interweaving of strands). You, intrepid traveler, will be learning how to throw a net into Hāna Bay, in the hopes of catching a fish, but every day native Hawaiians throw net to catch dinner to share with their &lsquo;OHāna. You&rsquo;ll be surprised how easily you&rsquo;ll catch on to readying the net to cast, and how fun it is to throw a perfect net into the ocean, pull it in and discover&hellip;</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-throw-net-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Hawaiian "Throw Net"</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-throw-net.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="40" position="6" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.5" sitemapTitle="Kite Fishing">
					<title>Kite Fishing</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-kite-fishing</slug>
						<pageTitle>Kite Fishing</pageTitle>
						<description>Learn the ropes of one of the most fun and interesting ways to fish.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, kite fishing, traditional fishing, modern fishing.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Kite Fishing</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Learn the history and technique of traditional and modern kite fishing in this interactive and unique offering. From Polynesia to Southeast Asia, many countries lay claim to its invention. No matter where it originated, using a kite is a great way to fish in areas difficult to navigate by boat. Whether you're able to reel in a catch or not, you'll love the experience as you listen to the soothing sounds of the waves and dip your kite in and out of the water.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-kite-fishing-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Kite Fishing</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-kite-fishing.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="41" position="7" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.6" sitemapTitle="Bike Holoholo">
					<title>Bike Holoholo</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-bike-holoholo</slug>
						<pageTitle>Bike Holoholo</pageTitle>
						<description>Take a bike cruise like no other as we explore Hāna’s gorgeous terrain and discover its culture.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, bike, holoholo, journey, tour, local, bicycle</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Bike Holoholo</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p><em>Holoholo</em> loosely translates to cruising, and there is no place to cruise like Hāna. Join us for a fun bike excursion as we visit a handful of local sites while learning about land use, culture, history and stewardship. You&rsquo;ll become acquainted with Hāna&rsquo;s sugar plantation days, understand the diversity of plants, connect with the architecture, re-live festivals and get a closer look at local town life.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-bike-holoholo-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Bike Holoholo</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-bike-holoholo.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="42" position="8" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.7" sitemapTitle="Photography">
					<title>Photography</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-photography</slug>
						<pageTitle>Photography</pageTitle>
						<description>Get the most out of every photographic shot with our hands-on tutoring.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, DSLR camera buff, photographers, rule of thirds, professional portraits, landscapes, photos, tutoring.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Photography</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Capture Your Journey</h2><p>Cerulean blue water. Iridescent beds of flowers. A loved one attempting to master stand up paddling. Expand your power of the point-and-shoot or SLR digital camera and unleash your inner photographer. In this basic photography class, receive hands-on tutoring covering the general anatomy and hidden functions of your individual cameras. You will leave more knowledgeable about the ins and outs of photography, armed with tried and true professional techniques for composing better images.</p>
					<h2>Landscape: Challenging Your Creative Eye</h2>
					<p>Visiting Hāna is definitely the time and place to take your photography to the next level. Capture the landscape around you like a pro and hone your digital camera creativity in this more advanced class. Learn how photographers use white balance, natural and artificial lightning, the rule of thirds and the golden mean to create professional looking landscape images.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-photography-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Photography</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-photography.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="43" position="9" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.8" sitemapTitle="Creative Outlet Series">
					<title>Creative Outlet Series</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-creative-outlet-series</slug>
						<pageTitle>Creative Outlet Series</pageTitle>
						<description>Release the artist within and discover the circle of energy as the creativity you express returns to empower and rejuvenate.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, creative, creativity, artist, artistic, artwork, art, inspiration, inspired</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Creative Outlet Series</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Some say creating artwork in a setting as beautiful as Hāna&rsquo;s can be just as relaxing as a massage. That&rsquo;s why we offer you pressure-free ways to release your inner creative. You&rsquo;ll be inspired as you focus on the relation between your soul and your surroundings through your choice of artistic outlet. Best of all, no experience or talent is needed to create something amazing you can bring home to remind you of your Travaasa journey.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-creative-outlet-series-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Creative Outlet Series</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-creative-outlet-series.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="44" position="10" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.9" sitemapTitle="ECOLOGY (HANA)">
					<title>Ecology</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-ecology</slug>
						<pageTitle>Ecology</pageTitle>
						<description>Explore and discover one of the world's richest and most diverse environments in a thrilling journey around Hāna.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, hawaii, canoe plants, taro, biodiversity, native flora</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Ecology</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>The beauty and biodiversity of Hawai&rsquo;i is unlike anywhere else on Earth. The islands form the most remote archipelago on earth, 2,500 miles from the nearest land mass. The native flora and fauna developed in isolation in the rich, volcanic soil, with new species occasionally arriving by accident via wind, water or wings. Early explorers also contributed, bringing plants and seeds endemic to their own culture. We invite you to learn more about Hawaii&rsquo;s ecological wonders and discover yet another reason why it&rsquo;s recognized the world over as paradise.</p>
					<h2>Canoe Plants/Taro</h2>
					<p>The story of these unique plants begins 1,300 years ago when Polynesian explorers loaded their canoes with a precious cargo of plants, shoots and seeds. These explorers not only had to sustain themselves throughout the journey, but it was very wise to bring a &ldquo;taste of home&rdquo; since they had no idea what awaited them. Now you have the opportunity to explore the property and learn how Hawaiians have used these unique plants to define their way of life. Plants like taro, believed to have the greatest life force of all foods.&nbsp;</p>
					<h2>Garden Walk</h2>
					<p>Join us for a journey around the beautiful Travaasa property as we learn about the lush plants and flowers that adorn our grounds, the rich history of the resort and the very special town and people of Hāna.</p>
					<h2>Tidal Pools</h2>
					<p>Join us on an ecological excursion to discover the marine life in the tidal pools of Hāna. On our exploration we&rsquo;ll visit several different pools on the reef, each with a different ecosystem. We&rsquo;ll take a look at a few of the undersea creatures native to Hawaii such as eels, crustaceans, and mollusks and examine early marine development. Finally, you&rsquo;ll learn about the cultural importance of the ocean in sustaining the Hawaiian people while understanding traditional gathering practices and food customs.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-ecology-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Ecology</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-ecology.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="45" position="11" sitemapId="4.1.1.3.10" sitemapTitle="Talk Story">
					<title>Talk Story</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-talk-story</slug>
						<pageTitle>Talk Story</pageTitle>
						<description>Get to know your fellow guests and staff with nightly gatherings around our fire pit.</description>
						<keywords> travaasa, Hāna, hana, fire pit, Hawaii, adventures, life, memories, story telling, Pele, sharing, ukulele, fun, nightly gathering.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Talk Story</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>The Hawaiian tradition of "talk story" is a cultural practice of information sharing, tradition building and reinforcement of a community&rsquo;s values passed from generation to generation. This nightly gathering around our fire pit allows you to get to know your fellow guests and the staff a little bit better. After all, this is a culture that knows how to sit together and talk. Talk about everything. The day. Life. Adventures. Memories. No two evenings are ever the same, whether it&rsquo;s sharing stories or an impromptu &lsquo;ukulele jam, or just listening to the crackle of the fire, every night will be a little bit different and a whole lot of fun.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-talk-story-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Talk Story</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-talk-story.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" parentId="1" secondaryNav="true" id="46" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.1.4" sitemapTitle="Fitness">
					<title>Fitness</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-fitness-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Fitness</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa fitness focuses on balance, core work and flexibility</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, fitness, toning, strengthening, body, classes, sessions, yoga, Wellness Pavillion, Banyan Tree, core work.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Fitness Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Strengthening and toning the body is a natural activity at Travaasa Hāna, and we offer a wide range of classes, sessions and everyday events to leave you feeling like a new person. And it just so happens, you&rsquo;ll have a beautiful environment to work out in, whether it&rsquo;s in our open-air yoga area under a gracious Banyan Tree, our serene &ldquo;all-doors-open-to-the-breezes&rdquo; Wellness Pavilion, or out on the wild Hāna coast.</p>
					<p>Our fitness Travaasas focus on balance, core work and flexibility. With this well-rounded selection, we&rsquo;re not promising miracles, but we just bet you&rsquo;ll leave here feeling better and stronger.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-fitness-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Fitness Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-fitness.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="47" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.1" sitemapTitle="YOGA">
					<title>Yoga</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-yoga</slug>
						<pageTitle>Yoga</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa yoga classes heal, detoxify and unify mind and body.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, vinyasa yoga, awareness, reduce stress, control weight, harmonize, heal, detoxify, unify body and mind, asana, yin, physical activity, hatha, sun salutations, breath, motion, gentle yoga.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Yoga for Mind and Body</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Yoga at Travaasa Hāna is unlike yoga anywhere else in the world. Our instructors bring years of training and knowledge, our yoga classes are varied and unique, and the location (outdoor or in our open-air Wellness Center) will reinvigorate you with its sheer beauty and calm. It&rsquo;s widely known that yoga is a wonderful technique to heal, detoxify and unify your mind and body. It can help fortify your awareness of movement, balance and intention, in addition to strengthening your body (through vinyasa yoga). No matter your age, strength or flexibility level, anyone can do yoga with the right attitude and the right teacher. And if you are new to yoga, you&rsquo;ll find a physical path that harmonizes mind, body and soul. Yoga combines physical activity with breath to reduce stress, control weight, relieve lower back pain and enhance focus.&nbsp;</p>
					<h2>Basic</h2>
					<p>A peaceful form of exercise helping you increase flexibility, strength, balance and inner awareness.&nbsp; Connecting breath and body movement that will enhance each posture as you relax and inhale the tropical warmth of Hāna's fresh air and rejuvenating powers.&nbsp; All levels are welcome.</p>
					<h2>Inner Landscape</h2>
					<p>This soft, gentle yoga experience is designed to help you open your body and mind. Move into unique postures designed to emulate the distinctive, varying landscapes of Hawaii as you focus on your senses and soak in the beauty of Hāna.</p>
					<h2>Gentle Hatha</h2>
					<p>Hatha may be the most common form of yoga practiced by Westerners, but practicing it in Hāna elevates it to an uncommonly spectacular level. We&rsquo;ll start with traditional Sun Salutations (a linking of breath and motion) and other Hatha yoga poses. First timers are invited to join more seasoned practitioners. This is a class aimed at everyone and moves at a pace you&rsquo;re comfortable with. And really, what&rsquo;s the hurry? The goal is to energize your body and mind.&nbsp;</p>
					<h2>Yin</h2>
					<p>If you&rsquo;re a yoga practitioner, you may be doing only one part the asana practice. Challenge yourself with the slower, gentler discipline of Yin Yoga. Some consider it the original form of asana practice that is now being &ldquo;re-discovered&rdquo; by students. Yin practitioners can remain in postures from one to an amazing twenty minutes because it targets the connective tissues. These are the ligaments, bone and joints of the body that are not exercised much in other forms of yoga. Yin strengthens the hips and lower back and increases the flow of energy, allowing you to sit for long periods in contemplative meditation. This class is open everyone with an interest in yoga.&nbsp;</p>
					<h2>Flow</h2>
					<p>Challenge your body and mind with a Vinyasa flow style class. Vinyasa yoga focuses on integrating breath with movement, awareness with alignment and strength with flexibility. In this class you will explore how individual yoga postures and sequences work together by creating a smooth series of postures that run together and seem to flow like a rhythmic dance.</p>
					<h2>Spine</h2>
					<p>Yogis say youth is determined by the flexibility of your spine: if we can keep a healthy spine, the rest of the body follows suit. In this class we will practice a combination of back bends and forward bends to strengthen and bring flexibility to the spine. Lower back pain and upper back stress are some of the most common health complaints of adults. The best way to avoid backaches is to take care of your spine on a daily basis. Here we will also learn some gentle stretches you can do on your own to relieve and prevent back pain. There are no quick fixes for back pain, but this exercise set is an effective maintenance program.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-yoga-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Yoga</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-yoga.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="48" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.2" sitemapTitle="OUTDOOR CIRCUIT">
					<title>Outdoor Circuit</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-outdoor-circuit</slug>
						<pageTitle>Outdoor Circuit</pageTitle>
						<description>Outdoor workout at Travaasa that gives you maximum results in minimum time by mixing up moves and changing intensity.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, intervals, circuit training, fitness, challenge, body, mind, workout, exercise, beach.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Outdoor Circuit</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Get ready to go through some tough intervals that make your heart rate soar. Circuit training delivers maximum results in a minimum amount of time while promoting all-around fitness. We&rsquo;ll challenge your body and your mind as we mix up the moves and the intensity of the workout to keep you motivated - all the while being surrounded by 360˚ views of stunning scenery. But what makes our circuit unlike any other is that we&rsquo;ll exercise using the natural landmarks around our beautiful Hāna property. And our circuit wouldn&rsquo;t be complete if we didn&rsquo;t hit the beach!</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-outdoor-circuit-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Outdoor Circuit</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-outdoor-circuit.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="49" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.3" sitemapTitle="CORE CONDITIONING">
					<title>Core Conditioning</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-core-conditioning</slug>
						<pageTitle>Core Conditioning</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa core work tones abs, lower back and glutes, and improves balance.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, core, muscles, tone, abs, glutes, lower back, workout, balance, stability balls, mana.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Core Conditioning</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p><em>Mana</em> is a divine spiritual power or energy. It&rsquo;s a power that comes from within flowing through all of us and giving us the power to do what we believe we can do. So it&rsquo;s no small wonder that our 30-minute core class will make you feel like you can conquer the world. You just have to believe. Tone your abs, lower back and glues in this intense workout. You&rsquo;ll improve core strength, balance and total body function using stability balls and gravity-resistant exercises.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-core-conditioning-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Core Conditioning</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-core-conditioning.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="50" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.4" sitemapTitle="Pilates">
					<title>Pilates</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-pilates</slug>
						<pageTitle>Pilates</pageTitle>
						<description>Transform the way your body looks, feels and performs without building excess bulk.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, pilates, strength, posture, flexibility, agility, Wellness Center, mat, graceful movement.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Pilates</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>You're here to stretch your imagination, not to mention your body. And there’s nothing else like our Pilates class held in the drop-dead gorgeous setting of our Wellness Center to do both. Pilates is designed to transform the way your body looks, feels and performs, building strength without excess bulk. This basic all-level Pilates class on the mat teaches awareness, good posture and easy, graceful movement.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-pilates-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Pilates</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-pilates.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="51" position="6" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.5" sitemapTitle="Barre">
					<title>Barre</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-barre</slug>
						<pageTitle>Barre</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa barre exercises lengthen, strengthen and create lean dancer muscles.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, barre, exercises, Hawaiian, high-energy, fitness, ballet, sculpts, muscles, dancers.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Barre</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Barre can help you get in shape for baring it all at the beach or pool. Barre exercises are based on the movements and training habits of premier dancers. But luckily for you, you don’t have to be a dancer to reap the benefits of barre exercises. A high-energy, unique fitness experience that takes place both at a traditional ballet bar and floor based exercises, barre sculpts muscles to become longer, leaner and stronger.</p><p>And who doesn’t want that?</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-barre-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Barre</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-barre.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="52" position="7" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.6" sitemapTitle="Martial Arts Conditioning">
					<title>Martial Arts Conditioning</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-martial-arts-conditioning</slug>
						<pageTitle>Martial Arts Conditioning</pageTitle>
						<description>Transform the way your body looks, feels and performs without building excess bulk.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, pilates, strength, posture, flexibility, agility, Wellness Center, mat, graceful movement.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Martial Arts Conditioning</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p><p>Kick stress&rsquo;s gluteus maximus with a class that will get your heart rate pumping. This fun workout uses the principles of many different martial arts disciplines (that&rsquo;s only natural when you consider Hawai&rsquo;i is the crossroads of the Pacific). We&rsquo;ll even delve into the ancient Hawaiian art of self-defense called lua. Back in the day, skilled warriors knew around 300 moves that they used with devastating effect.</p></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-martial-arts-conditioning-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Martial Arts Conditioning</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-martial-arts-conditioning.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="53" position="8" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.7" sitemapTitle="COASTAL WORKOUT">
					<title>Coastal Workout </title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-coastal-workout</slug>
						<pageTitle>Coastal Workout</pageTitle>
						<description>Enjoy a great full-body workout that feels even better with the Pacific Ocean as a backdrop.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, full-body, coastal workout, infinity pool </keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Coastal Workout</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Tired of exercising in a dark, enclosed gym that forces you to work out and <em>then</em> get in your cardio? Our coastal workout allows you to experience both at the same time as you walk along the stunning Pacific Ocean. You'll be carrying a sand-filled "pack" that intensifies your jog and serves as your resistance for a full-body workout. After you get done with this experience you'll be ready to grab a smoothie and relax by the infinity pool.&nbsp;</p>
					]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-coastal-workout-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Coastal Workout</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-coastal-workout.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="54" position="9" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.8" sitemapTitle="Simplified Fitness">
					<title>Simplified Fitness</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-simplified-fitness</slug>
						<pageTitle>Simplified Fitness</pageTitle>
						<description>No fancy health club or equipment necessary. We'll show you an uncomplicated, effective workout that simply makes you feel great.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, simplified, fitness, bosu</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Simplified Fitness</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Use your own body's own resistance to strengthen, define, and challenge your muscles in this invigorating workout that can be done anytime, anywhere. You'll be amazed at the vast range of exercises you can do with just yourself, a fit ball and a bosu.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-simplified-fitness-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Simplified Fitness</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-simplified-fitness.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="55" position="10" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.9" sitemapTitle="COASTAL WALK AND STRETCH">
					<title><![CDATA[Coastal Walk &amp; Stretch]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-coastal-walk-and-stretch</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Coastal Walk &amp; Stretch]]></pageTitle>
						<description>A good morning is redefined as you take a morning walk along the gorgeous Hāna coastline and complete a light workout that leaves you refreshed and energized.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, maui, coastal walk, coastline, stretch</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Coastal Walk &amp; Stretch]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Start your day with a walk along the beautiful Maui coastline. You&rsquo;ll stop frequently along the way to take in breathtaking natural features as you wake your body for the day ahead. We&rsquo;ll teach you a non-static technique known active isolated stretching that helps improve circulation, increase the elasticity of muscle and fascia, develop joint range of motion and reduce stress.&nbsp;</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-coastal-walk-stretch-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Coastal Walk &amp; Stretch]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-coastal-walk-stretch.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="5" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="56" position="11" sitemapId="4.1.1.4.10" sitemapTitle="Foam Rollers">
					<title>Foam Rollers</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-foam-rollers</slug>
						<pageTitle>Foam Rollers</pageTitle>
						<description>Release muscular tension with a rolling massage that helps increase flexibility.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, foam rollers, Hawaiian, flexibility, massage, muscular, tension, shoulders, relaxing, balance, core muscles.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Foam Rollers</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>One of the reasons you might be here is for a relaxing, stress-free, pressure-free Hawaiian experience. Of course, you may need some help releasing all the muscular tension civilization has placed squarely on your shoulders. We suggest foam rollers, a body rolling exercise that helps you release muscular tension with a rolling massage that feels great and helps increase flexibility. You&rsquo;ll also improve balance, core muscles, stability and total body function.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-foam-rollers-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Foam Rollers</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-foam-rollers.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="6" primarySection="1" parentId="1" secondaryNav="true" id="57" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.1.5" sitemapTitle="Spa and Wellness">
					<title><![CDATA[Wellness]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-spa-and-wellness</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Wellness]]></pageTitle>
						<description>Our spa and wellness offerings are designed for your inner and outer needs.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, wellness, inner, outer, balanced state of mind, healthy body, stretch, meditation, yoga, posture, breath work.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Wellness Overview]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Our spa &amp; wellness offerings are designed for your inner and outer needs. A balanced state of mind, coupled with a managed stress life, a healthy body and a satisfied soul, gives focus and a point of view to our lives. We achieve that through meditation, stretch, yoga, posture and breath work. Not to mention stimulating health-oriented consultations that will pique your curiosity. Think of these workshops as a wellness toolkit you&rsquo;ll be able to refer to again and again after you leave here.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-wellness-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Wellness Overview]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-wellness.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="6" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="58" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.1.5.1" sitemapTitle="HĀ BREATH">
					<title>Hā Breath</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-ha-breath</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hā Breath</pageTitle>
						<description>Hā is an ancient ritual that promotes a general sense of well-being and enriches mind, body and spirit.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, hā, ha, mind, body, spirit, coastline, Pacific, yoga, experience, balance.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hā Breath</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p><em>Hā</em> means breath&mdash;the source of life. Clearly this class enriches your mind, body and spirit the island way. In the most natural way possible, the tradition of <em>Hā</em> shows you how easily tension is released and self-imposed barriers broken when you simply relax and allow your body, and your world, to work. Our tranquil setting offers stunning views of the incredible lush greens that surround our property and the deep, blue Pacific. Whether you&rsquo;re a novice or yoga expert you&rsquo;ll enjoy our Hā experience.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-ha-breath-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Hā Breath</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-ha-breath.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="6" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="59" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.1.5.2" sitemapTitle="Meditation">
					<title>Meditation</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-guided-meditation</slug>
						<pageTitle>Meditation</pageTitle>
						<description>Meditation starts with guided practice and the use of chakra points to learn acceptance and letting go.</description>
						<keywords> travaasa, Hāna, hana, Hawaiian, candelight, meditation, yoga, chakra</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Guided Meditation</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>In this Travaasa, we help demystify the ancient practice of meditation&mdash;bringing awareness to our moment-to-moment experiences. This simple&mdash;but not easy&mdash;practice of acceptance, letting go, non-striving and suspension of the judgmental mind leaves us with a deep sense of openness and receptivity to ourselves, to others and to the moment as it unfolds.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-guided-meditation-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Guided Meditation</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-guided-mediation.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="6" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="60" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.1.5.3" sitemapTitle="CHI MOVEMENT">
					<title>Chi Movement</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-chi-movement</slug>
						<pageTitle>Chi Movement</pageTitle>
						<description>Chi Movement is a moving meditation exercise.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, I Chi Flow, Tai Chi, Chi Gong, meditation, Hawaiian.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Chi Movement</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>This class has a decidedly Hawaiian vibe to it. It&rsquo;s not about sweating and puffing. Instead, it focuses on feeling calm, refreshed and energized by incorporating key components of Tai Chi, Chi Gong and I Chi Flow. Introduce your body and mind to the concept of &ldquo;moving meditation&rdquo; exercise. Unlike calisthenics, this integral movement enhances life energy slowly by progressively making the body more flexible and improving overall health.&nbsp;</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-chi-movement-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Chi Movement</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-chi-movement.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="true" id="61" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.2" sitemapTitle="The Spa at Travaasa Hāna">
					<title>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-the-spa-at-travaasa-hana</slug>
						<pageTitle>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</pageTitle>
						<description>A range of transformative therapeutic experiences utilizing Hāna’s natural resources pampers and prepares you as your escape begins with a journey back to center.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, therapeutic, tranquility, health, balance, wellness, spirit</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to The Spa at Travaasa Hāna, a deeply relaxing sanctuary of peace and tranquility enhanced by Hāna&rsquo;s natural tropical beauty. We believe true health and balance come from the gifts of the earth and elements of nature, and that Hāna is a place of innate nurturing and well-being.</p>
					<p>At The Spa at Travaasa Hāna, we gratefully utilize the incredible bounty of Hāna, using its abundant plants, minerals and water to blend in our teas and create natural body and face products and treatments. The wide variety of therapeutic services we offer prepares our guests to experience Hāna more fully, thus restoring feelings of balance and wellness to body, mind, spirit and emotion</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="62" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.2.1" sitemapTitle="Reservations">
					<title>Reservations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-reservations</slug>
						<pageTitle>Reservations</pageTitle>
						<description>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna offers a wide range of journeys and experiences to make your time here truly memorable. Choose the programs that call to you, or talk to us and we’ll help you put together a program that’s perfect for you.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, spa retreat, wellness program, wellness, reservations</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Reservations</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>To make reservations at The Spa at Travaasa Hāna for a spa treatment or spa package, to plan a spa retreat, or to inquire about a customized wellness program, please call 808-270-5290.</p>
					<h1>Spa Information</h1>
					<h2>Spa Concierge</h2>
					<p><br />We are at your service during spa hours to address your questions and to customize your spa experience for maximum benefit and enjoyment. When making your spa reservations, advise our Spa Concierge of any health concerns, allergies or special requests to ensure a healthy and enjoyable experience.</p>
					<h2>Cancellations</h2>
					<p>Please keep in mind that the treatment times are reserved especially for you. There is a 50% charge for any changes or cancellations to appointments with less than 6 hours notice, or Spa Packages with less than 24 hours notice. No-shows will be charged in full. As a courtesy to all guests, late arrivals will only receive the remaining available appointment time.</p>
					<h2>Arrival Time</h2>
					<p>Please arrive at least 30 minutes prior to your appointment time to take full advantage of our facilities. If you arrive late, your treatment will end on time so that the next guest will not be inconvenienced.</p>
					<h2>Spa Attire</h2>
					<p>Please arrive wearing attire that is comfortable for you. You will need a bathing suit for use of the outdoor water facilities. We provide robes and slippers.</p>
					<h2>Leave Everything Behind</h2>
					<p>Please leave valuables, cigarettes, alcoholic beverages, cell phones and pagers in your Cottage. Minimum age requirement for spa guests is 16 years of age.</p>
					<h2>Our Therapists</h2>
					<p>As spa professionals, our therapists are well-trained to ensure your comfort and privacy at all times. A male, female or specific therapist may be requested. However, we cannot guarantee their availability.</p>
					<h2>Gratuities</h2>
					<p>For your convenience, an 18% gratuity will be added to each treatment.</p>
					<h2>For Your Comfort</h2>
					<p>Please shower before all treatments. Avoid shaving one day prior to body scrubs. Rest and avoid vigorous activity for at least one hour after treatments, and drink water before and after all therapies.</p>
					<h2>In-Room Massage</h2>
					<p>Enjoy massages in the privacy of your Cottage for an additional $40 per person.</p>
					<h2>Pregnancy</h2>
					<p>We suggest several different treatments for pregnant women. Please notify us as to the length of term when making an appointment.</p>
					<h2>Day Guests</h2>
					<p>Clients who are not guests of the hotel will be charged a Day Guest Fee of $25 per person per day when making any spa appointment. Appointments are required for non-guests.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-reservations-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Reservations</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-reservations.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="63" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.2.2" sitemapTitle="Body Treatments">
					<title>Body Treatments</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-body-treatments</slug>
						<pageTitle>Body Treatments</pageTitle>
						<description>Body treatments at Travaasa Hāna are designed to energize or soothe.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hāna, spa, spa treatment, body treatment, body wrap, clay, reducing stress and tension, exfoliate, exfoliation, cleanse, stimulate</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Body Treatments</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Body treatments at Travaasa Hāna are designed to energize or soothe, and at Travaasa Hāna we have a special name for the special herbal treatments we use: Pālā&lsquo;au Kino (heal the body with herbs).</p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;āla (&ldquo;To Arise&rdquo;) Refining Clay Body Wrap</h2>
					<p>Unrefined, sun-dried pink clay blended with wild-crafted, organic myrtle, sandalwood, lemon, sea algae and wild rose defines this deeply cleansing, purifying and toning experience. Witch hazel, organic fig and rosemary help balance and clear the mind while reducing stress and tension trapped in the body. Clay has been used throughout the ages for its healing, cooling, anti-inflammatory and regenerative properties. This treatment includes a gentle exfoliation, comforting clay body wrap and Harmonizing Ear &amp; Scalp massage. Healing botanicals of organic cypress, juniper and hyssop also help cleanse, tone, moisturize and deeply stimulate your skin.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $175</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;ōla hou (&ldquo;To Restore Life&rdquo;) Aromatherapy Massage and Warm Body Wrap</h2>
					<p>Enjoy the calming and genuine healing properties of pure organic essential oils. This 90-minute customized massage soothes the soul with your choice of Relaxing, Balancing, Warming, Energizing or Fitness premium massage oil blends. Your massage is followed with a warm body wrap to allow this pure oil blend to deeply penetrate your skin. During the wrap, a Harmonizing Ear &amp; Scalp Massage is performed to usher your body and psyche into a state of total relaxation and renewal.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $185</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;opa&rsquo;a (&ldquo;To Complete&rdquo;) Detoxifying Body Massage &amp; Algae Wrap</h2>
					<p>Unrefined, sun-dried green clay blended with the purest spirulina defines this experience. Finding balance and clarity using organic myrtle, lemon and juniper combined with sandalwood and olive stone to regenerate, oxygenate and clarify your skin. Skin will be restored, rehydrated and protected by our organic myrtle, cypress, hyssop, juniper, rosemary and other healing plants and flowers, leaving it feeling pure, clean, firm and smooth. A Swedish massage finishes this age-defying treatment.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $185</strong></p>
					<h1>Add-On Treatments</h1>
					<h2>Mālama Maka (&ldquo;Care for the Eyes&rdquo;) Soothing &amp; Healing Eye Treatment</h2>
					<p>Applied during mask resting time. Treat and revive tired or stressed eyes with Amala&rsquo;s mineral-rich eye pack. This eye pack will work to restore tone and elasticity and assist in minimizing dark circles, puffiness and fine lines while regenerating and oxygenating your skin. The delicate eye area will be soothed, remineralized and rehydrated by our organic seed oils, crafted from plants and flowers which are vital for the health and repair of our skin.</p>
					<p><strong>$40</strong></p>
					<h2>&lsquo;Ānainai Pa&rsquo;akai (&ldquo;To Scrub with Salt&rdquo;) Sea Mineral Salt Scrub</h2>
					<p>A perfect add-on to any massage. Unrefined, mineral rich sea salt will gently buff away dry flaky skin, leaving your body silky smooth.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes - $65</strong></p>
					<h2>&lsquo;Ānainai &lsquo;Ili (&ldquo;To Scrub the Skin&rdquo;) Dry Brush Treatment</h2>
					<p>Stimulate the lymphatic system with this massage add-on. Dry skin will be brushed off, while stimulating the lymphatic system to help create perfect balance.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes - $50</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-body-treatments-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Body Treatments</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-body-treatments.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="64" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.2.3" sitemapTitle="Facials">
					<title>Facials</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-facials</slug>
						<pageTitle>Facials</pageTitle>
						<description>We believe that natural beauty is best restored using natural remedies.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hāna, spa treatment, spa, facial, natural beauty, skin care, heal, healing herbs</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Pālā&rsquo;au &lsquo;Ili (Heal the Skin with Herbs) Skin Care]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>We believe that natural beauty is best restored using natural remedies. At Travaasa Hāna we call it Pālā&lsquo;au &lsquo;lli (heal the skin with herbs). Let us create a facial expressly for you and your skin type, then lay back and relax as we soothe, heal and clarify your skin with local clay, wild-crafted oils, plants, minerals and flowers.</p>
					<h2>Ka &lsquo;Oi (&ldquo;The Best&rdquo;) Most Pure Facial</h2>
					<p>Throughout time, blue lotus has symbolized purity of mind and body. Blue lotus, and other healing plants, seed oils and flowers such as jasmine, papaya, coco bean, green tea and green algae inspired this balancing, clarifying and restorative treatment. Indian Rassoul clay is incorporated for its deep-cleansing and healing properties. Our signature Vedic Marma Cleansing Technique, combined with wild-crafted bamboo, tiger grass and ginger, provides essential nutrition and replenishes amino acids to purify the skin as it restores balance. The rare blue lotus provides essential nutrition for a pure, healthy complexion. Great for all skin types.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $195</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;oma&rsquo;ema&rsquo;e (&ldquo;To Purify&rdquo;) Oil Control Facial</h2>
					<p>Restore balance, clarity and radiance to skin inspired by the healing plants and flowers of the Islands. Fair-trade rice germ, blue lotus, bamboo, algae extract and green and white clays help control excessive oil production and remove clogging impurities from skin. Wild-crafted tiger grass, tonka, macadamia and organic aloe, ginger and lemon help heal blemishes and promote clear skin. Organic green and white teas provide antioxidant protection, soothe skin and even skin tone for a pure, clear and healthy complexion. Perfect for oily and combination skin.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;opahe&rsquo;e (&ldquo;To Hydrate&rdquo;) Deep Moisturizing Facial</h2>
					<p>Quench dry, dehydrated skin with our organic, fair-trade cultivated and custom-distilled jasmine, along with organic papaya, jojoba and shea butter. Soothing fruits and healing herbs will restore lasting hydration and elasticity while protecting skin from free radical damage. Fine lines and uneven skin texture are smoothed by clove bud, lychee, rosewood and turmeric. The healing power of jasmine and other South Pacific plant ingredients replenish and sustain the skin&rsquo;s moisture and pono (balance) for a silky smooth texture and healthy, even tone. Essential for dehydrated, tired or jetlagged skin.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;omālena (&ldquo;To Tighten&rdquo;) Firming Facial</h2>
					<p>Nourish, rejuvenate and firm your skin with this luxurious and highly effective facial. A combination of organic jasmine, avocado, macadamia nut and papaya gently hydrates. The perfect blend of organic cocoa bean, acerola, damask rose, sandalwood and hibiscus rejuvenates and brightens your skin. Restorative fruits and plants such as andiroba, neroli and buriti will smooth fine lines and renew elasticity of the skin. Sun-dried sea algae, organic aloe, green coffee oil and licorice root trap and remove impurities, leaving your skin firmer, brighter with a more radiant and youthful skin tone.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;omalu (&ldquo;To Protect&rdquo;) Hāna Remineralizing Facial</h2>
					<p>Unrefined white and pink clays blended with the purest spirulina define this facial experience. Healing organic plants and flowers nourish parched skin. Inherent minerals will regenerate, oxygenate and deeply stimulate your skin. Your skin will gently absorb the minerals, vitamins and moisture from our organic cocoa bean, acai, andiroba, brazil nut, island plants and flowers, leaving skin brighter, firmer, smoother, more youthful. Great for all skin types, especially mature or long-term sun damaged skin.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $140</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;opiha (&ldquo;To Replenish&rdquo;) Soothing Skin Facial</h2>
					<p>Sun-dried, white clay has been used by indigenous cultures throughout the ages for its healing, cooling, anti-inflammatory and regenerative properties. Our organic, botanical facial uses white clay to calm and nurture sensitive or overexposed skin back to healthy balance. Organic jasmine, shea butter, aloe, rose, papaya and other healing plants and flowers will replenish the skin&rsquo;s moisture level and restore a healthy, even tone. Sensitive skin and sunburned skin will also benefit from this facial.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Kāne (Gentleman&rsquo;s) Facial</h2>
					<p>The healing blue lotus has come to symbolize purity and balance. Our gentleman&rsquo;s deeply cleansing and hydrating facial employs wild-crafted blue lotus, algae extract, rice germ, bamboo, ginger, lemon and tiger grass to exfoliate and purify the skin and decongest pores. Perfect for a man&rsquo;s skin, this facial provides the full spectrum of skin benefits as nature intended.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Hō&rsquo;ae&rsquo;ae (&ldquo;To Make Soft&rdquo;) Purifying Back Treatment</h2>
					<p>Restore balance, clarity and radiance to your skin with this back treatment inspired by the healing properties of rice germ, blue lotus, bamboo, algae extract and green and white clays. Control excessive oil production and remove clogging impurities from skin. Tiger grass and lemon help heal blemishes and promote clear skin; green and white teas provide antioxidant protection, soothe skin and even skin tone for a pure, healthy complexion.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-facials-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Facials</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-facials.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="65" position="5" sitemapId="4.1.2.4" sitemapTitle="Hands, Feet and Scalp">
					<title><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-hands-feet-and-scalp</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></pageTitle>
						<description>Head, hands, feet, they’re how we engage the world and perhaps our hardest working parts. Our natural treatments strengthen and energize, leaving you feeling healthy and nourished.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, head, scalp, hands, feet, treatment</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Hāna Hydrating Hand Treatment</h2>
					<p>Soften and smooth dehydrated skin with the fruits and flowers of Southeast Asia. Hands are exfoliated with organic olive stone and salt, and then wrapped in a detoxifying myrtle and clay mask. Organic jasmine, papaya, shea butter and jojoba strengthen the skin&rsquo;s moisture barrier and help prevent signs of aging for smooth, healthy hands.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes, $65</strong></p>
					<h2>Hāna Detoxifying Foot Treatment</h2>
					<p>Myrtle has a long reputation for deep cleansing. Feet are soaked in organic myrtle salt water, exfoliated with organic olive stone and salt and wrapped in a detoxifying myrtle and clay mask. Our organic myrtle, cypress, hyssop and juniper will purify, cleanse, refresh, smooth and refine the skin, leaving your feet feeling silky, smooth and energized.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes - $75</strong></p>
					<h2>Aromatherapy Scalp Treatment</h2>
					<p>This wonderful scalp treatment uses herbal oils of cinnamon and clove to stimulate and nourish your hair and scalp.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-hands-feet-scalp-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-hands-feet-scalp.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="66" position="6" sitemapId="4.1.2.5" sitemapTitle="Massage Therapy">
					<title>Massage Therapy</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-massage-therapy</slug>
						<pageTitle>Massage Therapy</pageTitle>
						<description>Our therapists perform a range of rapturous, transportive massages capable of satisfying whatever your body needs, whether it’s a health kick of energy or deep, stress-relieving calm.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, massage, Swedish massage, therapy, tension, stress</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Massage Therapy</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Swedish Massage</h2>
					<p>This deeply relaxing and soothing massage uses long, flowing strokes to help reduce tension and stress, ease stiffness and gently increase circulation. Our signature coconut, rice bran and monoi oil is used during this massage.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $130/$185</strong></p>
					<h2>Deep Tissue Massage</h2>
					<p>Melt away deep-seated tension and pain. This massage will release muscle fatigue and toxicity, help to realign your posture and increase range of motion. Our signature rice bran, coconut and monoi oil is used during this massage.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $140/$195</strong></p>
					<h2>Hāpai (Pre-Natal) Massage</h2>
					<p>Perfect for that special mom-to-be. This massage can be performed in all stages of pregnancy and is designed to reduce fluid retention, increase muscle tone and soothe aching backs and necks.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $130</strong></p>
					<h2>Traditional Thai Massage</h2>
					<p>This ancient healing art of Thailand uses gentle compression, acupressure on specific energy lines, rhythmic stretching and warm herbal compresses. The yoga of massage. Thai massage garments are provided.</p>
					<p><strong>90 or 120 minutes - $195/$250</strong></p>
					<h2>Pōhaku Wela Hot Stone</h2>
					<p>In the traditions of Hawai&rsquo;i, smooth heated stones apply the elements of earth, air, fire and water to achieve a healing, centering, rejuvenating treatment as muscle tension melts.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $140/$195</strong></p>
					<h2>Hawaiian Lomilomi</h2>
					<p>Lomilomi is a powerful native Hawaiian healing tradition. Rhythmic strokes, joint movement and deep kneading open the body and soothe the soul. Enjoy your choice of aromatherapy signature oil blends - $10 additional.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $130/$185</strong></p>
					<h2>Reflexology</h2>
					<p>Reflexology uses a specific touch to stimulate points along meridian paths over the entire body. This treatment begins with a dry brush treatment over the feet and lower leg, followed by a detoxifying foot soak using organic myrtle, fig and juniper. A soothing hand and foot massage completes this treatment. Not recommended for pregnant women.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $130</strong></p>
					<h2>Aquatic Renewal Therapy</h2>
					<p>Experience a whole new level of bodywork in Maui&rsquo;s first resort aquatic therapy pool. Drift into deep levels of relaxation. As you float and stretch in the therapist&rsquo;s arms without the pull of gravity, the warm water supports your body evenly, releases tension and produces a deep sense of renewed well-being. A bathing suit is required.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $14</strong></p>
					<h2>Hō&rsquo;a&rsquo;ala (&ldquo;To Make Fragrant&rdquo;) Aromatherapy Oil</h2>
					<p>Added to any massage treatment.</p>
					<p><strong>$10</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-massage-therapy-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Massage Therapy</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-massage-therapy.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="67" position="7" sitemapId="4.1.2.6" sitemapTitle="Waxing Services">
					<title>Waxing Services</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-Waxing Services</slug>
						<pageTitle>Waxing Services</pageTitle>
						<description>xxx</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, waxing</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Waxing Services</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Lip</h2>
					<p><strong>15 minutes - $20</strong></p>
					<h2>Brow Shape</h2>
					<p><strong>15 minutes - $25</strong></p>
					<h2>Full Leg</h2>
					<p><strong>90 minutes &ndash; Starting at $90</strong></p>
					<h2>Bikini</h2>
					<p><strong>30 minutes &ndash; Starting at $75</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-waxing-services-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Waxing Services</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-waxing-services.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="68" position="8" sitemapId="4.1.2.7" sitemapTitle="Special Packages">
					<title>Special Packages</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-special-packages</slug>
						<pageTitle>Special Packages</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa provides you with different rate and package selections so that you can make the most of your time at Hāna. These special offerings help you design a journey that’s just right for you.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, special packages, couple’s vacation, couple’s getaway, couple’s escape.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Special Packages</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Hāna Couple&rsquo;s Escape</h2>
					<p>Relax together, in the privacy of our couple&rsquo;s spa suite. Share any 60-minute massage, followed by a 90 minute Body Treatment of your choice. Price per couple, does not include gratuity.</p>
					<p><strong>$590 per couple</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;okaulike (Total Balance)</h2>
					<p>Choose any 60-minute facial followed by any 90-minute massage. Does not include gratuity.</p>
					<p><strong>$285 per person</strong></p>
					<h2>Mālama Kino Package (Total Care)</h2>
					<p>Regular massage and body therapies increase circulation and promote overall health, giving your body, mind and spirit a renewed sense of well-being. Choose up to eight 60-minute treatments from our spa menu and enjoy the benefits of wellness. Allow us to customize a package for you. Speak to your spa concierge for help in designing your ultimate spa experience. This package is available for more than one person and must be prepaid. There are no refunds or reimbursements for unused treatments. Guests may use this package any time during their stay. Price does not include gratuity.</p>
					<p><strong>$950 per cottage</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-special-packages-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Special Packages</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-special-packages.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="7" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="69" position="9" sitemapId="4.1.2.8" sitemapTitle="Spa Facilities">
					<title>Spa Facilities</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-spa-facilities</slug>
						<pageTitle>Spa Facilities</pageTitle>
						<description>Our spa facilities submerse you in luxury and bring the beauty of Hāna into your relaxation and wellness experience. We invite you to enjoy our complete range of services and amenities for both men and women.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, luxury, wellness, experience, service, amenities</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Spa Facilities</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy our well-appointed men&rsquo;s and women&rsquo;s locker rooms complete with steam rooms, cold plunge pool, indoor and outdoor showers, robes, slippers, towels and personal amenities. Beverages, herbal tea and fresh fruit are provided in the relaxation lounge. Relax in our outdoor, lava-rock whirlpool and lounge overlooking Hāna Bay in a tropical garden setting. Browse our spa shop, which features a full line of nurturing products, clothing, books, music, jewelry, teas and more.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-facilities-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Spa Facilities</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-facilities.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="8" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="true" id="70" position="1" sitemapId="4.1.3" sitemapTitle="Dining">
					<title>Dining</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-dining-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Dining</pageTitle>
						<description>At Travaasa you’ll find organic, locally-sourced produce, meat, fish and dairy.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Hawaiian, Asian, Polynesian, health-conscious, vegetarian, vegan, nourish.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Dining Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Nourishment</h2>
					<p>With the incredible abundance and inspiration of Hāna to draw from, our Executive Chef has created a dining experience that&rsquo;s pure Travaasa &ndash; a celebration of life and the bounty of the earth that nourishes us body and soul. He&rsquo;s coined a name for his eclectic, creative culinary style: Hāna Fusion, a combination of techniques from classical to innovative blending bold flavors with a focus on in-season, local ingredients.</p>
					<p>The menu incorporates many diverse layers of culinary influence central to Hawaiian culture. Alongside signature local dishes, you&rsquo;ll find elements of Asian and Old World European cuisine. Here at Travaasa Hāna, it all gets mixed up in a delicious m&eacute;lange as our chef creates familiar yet unique dishes with a Polynesian flair. And in keeping with the health-conscious ethos of the Hawaiian people, we also offer an extensive selection of gourmet vegetarian and vegan foods. Everything we serve is made from scratch with health and balance in mind.</p>
					<p>During your stay you can expect to savor a wide range of inventive, ambrosial dishes, such as our own Pohole Fern Shoot Salad, a native Hawaiian favorite. Fish wrapped in Ti Leaves. Seaweed salad. Taro. Fish smoked with guava and mango wood. Lilikoi Mahi with Hawaiian sweet potato and ginger lime coconut sauce. And an Open-faced Smoked Chicken Salad Sandwich on house-made bread with a locally grown sprout salad.</p>
					<p>Travaasa is all about the experience, a reminder that life is for living, and living well, and we always want you to leave happy. Dine with us and that philosophy is clear with every bite. </p>
					<h2>Eating Well</h2>
					<p>The Islands are a land rich with nature&rsquo;s bounty. And we only select fresh, organic, locally-sourced produce, fish, meat and dairy. Premium foods that are in-season and in our area to bring you only the finest sustainable breakfast, lunch and dinner options. At Travaasa Hāna we like to nourish, not only the spirit, but also the body. Because good food means good health.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-dining-overview-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Dining Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-dining-overview.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="8" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="71" position="2" sitemapId="4.1.3.1" sitemapTitle="Dining Options">
					<title>Dining Options</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-dining-options</slug>
						<pageTitle>Dining Options</pageTitle>
						<description>Enjoy breakfast, lunch and dinner in our Ka’uiki dining room or Paniolo café.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, breakfast, lunch, dinner, fish, chicken, salads, burgers, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, Kauiki dining room, Paniolo café, Hāna Town Center, roadhouse.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Dining Options</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy breakfast, lunch or dinner in our dining room, Ka&rsquo;uiki, as well as lighter fare in our caf&eacute;, Paniolo Lounge. Or engage in spirited and always unpredictable discussions at our Chef&rsquo;s Table.</p>
					<p>You may also want to stroll up to the Hāna Ranch Restaurant in the Hāna Town Center. It&rsquo;s an eclectic ranch-style roadhouse featuring Polynesian inspired ranch fare. Enjoy fish, chicken, salads and burgers. There&rsquo;s even a take out window for those on the go.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-dining-options-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Dining Options</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-dining-options.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="8" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="72" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.3.2" sitemapTitle="Libations">
					<title>Libations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-libations</slug>
						<pageTitle>Libations</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa serves organic, biodynamic wines and craft and organic beers.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Tedeschi Vineyards, Maui Brewing Company, wine, beer, organic, biodynamic, handcrafted lagers and ales, Mai Tai.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Libations</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p><strong>Wine</strong> We offer a distinctive and varied wine list that mirrors our environmental values by featuring organic, biodynamic and sustainable wines made by boutique producers. The practice of biodynamics in winemaking has been gaining in popularity and biodynamic wines have stronger, clearer, more vibrant tastes, as well as wines that remain drinkable longer.</p>
					<p><strong>Beer</strong> Sticking with our locally-sourced credo, we offer handcrafted lagers and ales from the Maui Brewing Company. Their Bikini Blonde lager, Big Swell IPA and Coconut Porter are brewed from the finest natural and local ingredients. We also stock an exceptional selection of imported beers.</p>
					<p><strong>Cocktails</strong> When in Hawai&rsquo;i do as the Hawaiians do. Try a Hāna Mai Tai made with fresh juices and other Hāna favorites like the pineapple mojito and the Hāna Highway Delight.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-libations-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Libations</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-libations.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="8" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="false" id="73" position="4" sitemapId="4.1.3.3" sitemapTitle="Executive Chef">
					<title>Executive Chef</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-executive-chef</slug>
						<pageTitle>Executive Chef</pageTitle>
						<description>xxx</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, executive chef</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Executive Chef, Barry Villiarimo</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Chef Barry Villiarimo returned to Hāna in 2010, coming full circle to where his career began. Raised in Hāna, Chef Barry spent the previous twenty years heading up some of the finest hotel restaurants on the West Coast, including the Westin Bonaventure Hotel &amp; Suites in Los Angeles.</p>
					<p>With a focus on farm-to-table cuisine, coupled with a blending of indigenous Hawaiian ingredients whenever possible, Chef Barry&rsquo;s attention to healthy eating is the perfect complement to Travaasa Hāna&rsquo;s commitment to our guest&rsquo;s culinary enjoyment, health and well being.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-executive-chef-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Executive Chef</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-executive-chef.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
			
				<page section="9" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="true" id="74" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.4" sitemapTitle="Accommodations: Sea Ranch Cottages">
					<title>Accommodations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-accommodations-sea-ranch-cottages</slug>
						<pageTitle>Accommodations: Sea Ranch Cottages</pageTitle>
						<description>Sea Ranch Cottages offer an all-inclusive stay along with ocean views.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Sea Ranch Cottage, Honua Spa, adventures, lanai, Pacific, Wellness Classes, Hamoa Beach, breakfast, lunch, dinner, Makana Activities Center, all inclusive.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Accommodations: Sea Ranch Cottages</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>The awe-inspiring views of the Hāna Coastline from a Sea Ranch Cottage will take your breath away. All cottages have sweeping views of the Pacific. So we understand why you may never leave the lanai (porch). Your cottage is a haven.&nbsp; Reflecting the culture of &ldquo;Old Hawai&rsquo;i&rdquo;, the cottage&rsquo;s serenity makes it the ideal place to recharge and reconnect with each other. However, our world class spa awaits to pamper your body and soul. Adventures abound on and off the property. And local, fresh cuisine awaits.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-accomodations-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Sea Ranch Cottages</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-accomodations.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="10" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="true" id="75" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.5" sitemapTitle="Rates and Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages">
					<title><![CDATA[Rates & Packages]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-rates-and-packages-sea-ranch-cottages</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages]]></pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa barre exercises lengthen, strengthen and create lean dancer muscles.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, barre, exercises, Hawaiian, high-energy, fitness, ballet, sculpts, muscles, dancers.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Fall in Love with Travaasa Hāna and save 33%</h2>
					<p>For a limited time, enjoy a savings of 33 percent when booking a three night stay in one of our Sea Ranch Cottages.</p>
					<p>Guests will also receive:</p>
					    <ul>
					        <li>Full American breakfast daily</li>
					        <li>Free room upgrade at check-in (based on availability)</li>
					        <li>Access to participation in some of Travaasa Hāna’s most popular cultural and fitness activities including Lei making, hula lessons, ukulele lessons, a historical walking tour of the Town of Hāna, net fishing and more.</li>
					        <li>Complimentary access to bicycles, boogie boards and more.</li>
					    </ul>
					    <p>Prices start at just <strong>$216</strong> per person, per night and are valid on three-night stays taking place November 1 through December 15, 2011.</p>
					    <p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2&promo=fallspecial" target="_blank"
					    		onclick="_gaq.push(['_link', https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2&promo=fallspecial']); 
					    		return false;"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					 <br />
					 <h2>Total Travaasa</h2>
					<p>When you treat yourself to the Total Travaasa package in Hāna, you won&rsquo;t have to worry about a thing. In addition to accommodations at our Sea Ranch Cottages, all meals, snacks and non alcoholic beverages are included, as well as your choice of any 60 minute treatment from our award winning spa. Also included are all on-property activities as well as off property activities such as a coastal horseback ride. Or for really adventurous souls, try stand up paddling (Hoe he&rsquo;e nalu).</p>
					<p><strong>Rates begin at $799, double occupancy</strong> <em>(tax and service charge not included)</em></p>
					<p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<br />
					<h2>Sunrise &amp; Spa Package</h2>
					<p>The Hāna Sunrise &amp; Spa package includes accommodations in one of our Sea Ranch Cottages, a generous and healthy breakfast, access to many of the activities including daily Yoga, and a 60 minute spa treatment of your choice.</p>
					<p><strong>Rates begin at $675, double occupancy</strong> <em>(tax and service not included)</em></p>
					<p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<br />
					<h2>Travaasa Hāna Sunrise Package</h2>
					<p>Experience Travaasa Hāna and find out why so many people have chosen to discover the &ldquo;real Hawai&rsquo;i&rdquo; here and all we have to offer. Included with your accommodations in one of our Sea Ranch Cottages is a generous breakfast and access to many of the cultural activities featured throughout the property.</p>
					<p><strong>Rates begin at $520, double occupancy </strong> <em>(tax and service charge not included)</em></p>
					<p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<br />
					<p><em>Please note that all guests on the Sea Ranch Cottage side of the property must be 16 years or older (except during our Family Weeks).</em></p>
					<p><em>If you&rsquo;re not looking for a package experience, check out our <a class="address_ajax" href="/hana-garden-view-suites-overview">Garden View</a> stay options.</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-rates-packages-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Sea Ranch Cottages]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-all-inclusive-rates-packages.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="11" primarySection="1" secondaryNav="true" id="76" position="3" sitemapId="4.1.6" sitemapTitle="Off-Property Excursions">
					<title>Off-Property Excursions</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-off-property-excursions</slug>
						<pageTitle>Off-Property Excursions</pageTitle>
						<description>Off-property excursions let you get to know Hāna and Maui.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, black-sand beach, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, swimming, horseback riding, cultural center, ancestors, Hāna Bay, Maui Stables, Ono Organic Farms, Wai Anapanapa State Park, off-property, excursions, Hāna Cultural Center, Kahanu Garden, ‘Ōhe’o Gulch at Haleakalā National Park, Seven Pools, Waimoku Falls</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Off-Property Excursions</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Hāna Town Center</h2>
					<p>Get a glimpse of community life by taking a stroll through the Town Center and browse the shops. The bank, post office, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, florist, Hāna Ranch Store and several gift shops are located here. Town Center is just a five-minute walk from the hotel.</p>
					<h2>Wai&rsquo;ānapanapa State Park</h2>
					<p>Walk along the ancient &ldquo;King&rsquo;s Trail,&rdquo; explore a legendary freshwater cave, discover important archeological sites, visit Maui&rsquo;s only black-sand beach and of course, it all overlooks the Pacific Ocean.</p>
					<h2>Hāna Bay</h2>
					<p><em>Kapueokahi</em> (the lone owl) is commonly referred to as &ldquo;Hāna Bay.&rdquo; It was the major shipping port for the sugar companies. Today, this quarter-mile slice of black and white sand is a favorite with local families for swimming, snorkeling and strolling. Complimentary snorkeling equipment is available at the Concierge Desk.</p>
					<h2>Hāna Cultural Center</h2>
					<p>Just a short walk from Travaasa Hāna, the Cultural Center houses a fascinating collection of historical photos, documents and artifacts. The gift shop helps support the collections and any donation is greatly appreciated.</p>
					<p>Open Monday &ndash; Friday 10:00 a.m.&ndash;4:00 pm.</p>
					<h2>Kahanu Garden</h2>
					<p>The Garden is home to some of Hawai&rsquo;i&rsquo;s most precious treasures. <em>Pi&rsquo;ilanihale</em>, a <em>heiau</em> or temple, is believed to be the largest man-made, pre-Western structure in all of Polynesia. Self-guided tours are offered Monday&ndash;Friday 10:00 a.m.&ndash;2:00 p.m. by the National Tropical Botanical Gardens. Guided tours are available on Saturdays by appointment. Advance reservations are required.</p>
					<h2>&lsquo;Ōhe&rsquo;o Gulch at Haleakalā National Park</h2>
					<p>The Park features the famous &ldquo;Pools of &#332;heo&rdquo; &ndash; a series of cascading pools leading to the ocean. The Waimoku Falls Trail is a five-mile round trip hike that takes you through a bamboo forest to the 400-foot Waimoku Falls. NOTE: The Park is approximately 11 miles from Hāna town and we urge you to drive there with caution and heed all caution signs while at the park.</p>
					<h2>ONO Organic Farms</h2>
					<p>This family-owned farm where everything is hand picked and certified organic is aptly named. ONO is the Hawaiian word for delicious. You&rsquo;ll tour this pure organic paradise and enjoy a tropical fruit tasting adventure by sampling 12 varieties of tropical fruit and ONO-grown coffee.</p>
					<h2>Maui Stables</h2>
					<p>Go on a historical and cultural horseback ride through the ancient unspoiled landscape of Maui. This isn&rsquo;t your typical stable. Maui Stables is native owned and operated. The <em>Alaka&rsquo;i</em> (guides) and <em>Kako&rsquo;o</em> (apprentice) who accompany you can trace their family roots back hundreds of years. Each tour will begin with a <em>pule</em> (prayer) and <em>oli</em>, or call to our ancestors. Throughout the ride they&rsquo;ll share stories of their ancestors and the land.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-off-property-excursions-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Off-Property Excursions</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-off-property-excursions.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				
				
				<page section="1" primarySection="2" root="true" secondaryNav="true" id="77" position="3" sitemapId="4.2" sitemapTitle="Garden View Overview">
					<title>Garden View Suites</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-suites-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Garden View Suites Overview</pageTitle>
						<description>Our Garden View options offer an experience that’s truly Travaasa, with an a la carte flexibility that’s perfect for tailoring the journey just for you.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, getaway, family vacation, garden view</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Garden View Suites Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Our Garden View stay options are a wonderful way to experience all the beauty of Hāna and have access to the rich amenities and services offered at Travaasa. A welcoming environment for children and families, the Garden View suites are also an attractive option for those staying elsewhere in Maui who just want to experience Hāna and explore local beaches and parks.</p>
					<p>Guests of our Garden View suites have access to our dining and spa services on an &agrave; la carte basis, and guests age 16 and older can access programs and activities on the Sea Ranch side of the property.</p>
					<p>Here is what your Garden View stay includes: </p>
					<ul>
					<li>Makana Activities Center offerings &ndash; Choose from bicycle adventures, horseback riding, walking tours, stand up paddle board, &lsquo;ukulele lessons, net throwing and much, much more.</li>
					<li>Daily use of sports equipment &ndash; snorkel gear, bicycles, tennis rackets.</li>
					<li>Enjoyment of the Garden Pool.</li>
					<li>Unlimited access to the fitness room.</li>
					</ul>
					<p><em>* If you&rsquo;re looking for an all-inclusive experience, please take a look at our <a href="hana-experiences" class="address_ajax">Sea Ranch</a> stay options</em>.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-overview-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Garden View Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-overview.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="true" id="78" position="1" sitemapId="4.2.1" sitemapTitle="The Spa at Travaasa Hāna">
					<title>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-the-spa-at-travaasa-hana</slug>
						<pageTitle>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</pageTitle>
						<description>A range of transformative therapeutic experiences utilizing Hāna’s natural resources pampers and prepares you as your escape begins with a journey back to center.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, therapeutic, tranquility, health, balance, wellness, spirit</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to The Spa at Travaasa Hāna, a deeply relaxing sanctuary of peace and tranquility enhanced by Hāna&rsquo;s natural tropical beauty. We believe true health and balance come from the gifts of the earth and elements of nature, and that Hāna is a place of innate nurturing and well-being.</p>
					<p>At The Spa at Travaasa Hāna, we gratefully utilize the incredible bounty of Hāna, using its abundant plants, minerals and water to blend in our teas and create natural body and face products and treatments. The wide variety of therapeutic services we offer prepares our guests to experience Hāna more fully, thus restoring feelings of balance and wellness to body, mind, spirit and emotion</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="79" position="2" sitemapId="4.2.1.1" sitemapTitle="Reservations">
					<title>Reservations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-reservations</slug>
						<pageTitle>Reservations</pageTitle>
						<description>The Spa at Travaasa Hāna offers a wide range of journeys and experiences to make your time here truly memorable. Choose the programs that call to you, or talk to us and we’ll help you put together a program that’s perfect for you.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, spa retreat, wellness program, wellness, reservations</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Reservations</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>To make reservations at The Spa at Travaasa Hāna for a spa treatment or spa package, to plan a spa retreat, or to inquire about a customized wellness program, please call 808-270-5290.</p>
					<h2><br />Spa Information</h2>
					<h2>Spa Concierge</h2>
					<p><br />We are at your service during spa hours to address your questions and to customize your spa experience for maximum benefit and enjoyment. When making your spa reservations, advise our Spa Concierge of any health concerns, allergies or special requests to ensure a healthy and enjoyable experience.</p>
					<h2>Cancellations</h2>
					<p>Please keep in mind that the treatment times are reserved especially for you. There is a 50% charge for any changes or cancellations to appointments with less than 6 hours notice, or Spa Packages with less than 24 hours notice. No-shows will be charged in full. As a courtesy to all guests, late arrivals will only receive the remaining available appointment time.</p>
					<h2>Arrival Time</h2>
					<p>Please arrive at least 30 minutes prior to your appointment time to take full advantage of our facilities. If you arrive late, your treatment will end on time so that the next guest will not be inconvenienced.</p>
					<h2>Spa Attire</h2>
					<p>Please arrive wearing attire that is comfortable for you. You will need a bathing suit for use of the outdoor water facilities. We provide robes and slippers.</p>
					<h2>Leave Everything Behind</h2>
					<p>Please leave valuables, cigarettes, alcoholic beverages, cell phones and pagers in your Cottage. Minimum age requirement for spa guests is 16 years of age.</p>
					<h2>Our Therapists</h2>
					<p>As spa professionals, our therapists are well-trained to ensure your comfort and privacy at all times. A male, female or specific therapist may be requested. However, we cannot guarantee their availability.</p>
					<h2>Gratuities</h2>
					<p>For your convenience, an 18% gratuity will be added to each treatment.</p>
					<h2>For Your Comfort</h2>
					<p>Please shower before all treatments. Avoid shaving one day prior to body scrubs. Rest and avoid vigorous activity for at least one hour after treatments, and drink water before and after all therapies.</p>
					<h2>In-Room Massage</h2>
					<p>Enjoy massages in the privacy of your Cottage for an additional $40 per person.</p>
					<h2>Pregnancy</h2>
					<p>We suggest several different treatments for pregnant women. Please notify us as to the length of term when making an appointment.</p>
					<h2>Day Guests</h2>
					<p>Clients who are not guests of the hotel will be charged a Day Guest Fee of $25 per person per day when making any spa appointment. Appointments are required for non-guests.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-reservations-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Reservations</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-reservations.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="80" position="3" sitemapId="4.2.1.2" sitemapTitle="Body Treatments">
					<title>Body Treatments</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-body-treatments</slug>
						<pageTitle>Body Treatments</pageTitle>
						<description>Body treatments at Travaasa Hāna are designed to energize or soothe.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hāna, spa, spa treatment, body treatment, body wrap, clay, reducing stress and tension, exfoliate, exfoliation, cleanse, stimulate</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Body Treatments</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Body treatments at Travaasa Hāna are designed to energize or soothe, and at Travaasa Hāna we have a special name for the special herbal treatments we use: Pālā&lsquo;au Kino (heal the body with herbs).</p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;āla (&ldquo;To Arise&rdquo;) Refining Clay Body Wrap</h2>
					<p>Unrefined, sun-dried pink clay blended with wild-crafted, organic myrtle, sandalwood, lemon, sea algae and wild rose defines this deeply cleansing, purifying and toning experience. Witch hazel, organic fig and rosemary help balance and clear the mind while reducing stress and tension trapped in the body. Clay has been used throughout the ages for its healing, cooling, anti-inflammatory and regenerative properties. This treatment includes a gentle exfoliation, comforting clay body wrap and Harmonizing Ear &amp; Scalp massage. Healing botanicals of organic cypress, juniper and hyssop also help cleanse, tone, moisturize and deeply stimulate your skin.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $175</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;ōla hou (&ldquo;To Restore Life&rdquo;) Aromatherapy Massage and Warm Body Wrap</h2>
					<p>Enjoy the calming and genuine healing properties of pure organic essential oils. This 90-minute customized massage soothes the soul with your choice of Relaxing, Balancing, Warming, Energizing or Fitness premium massage oil blends. Your massage is followed with a warm body wrap to allow this pure oil blend to deeply penetrate your skin. During the wrap, a Harmonizing Ear &amp; Scalp Massage is performed to usher your body and psyche into a state of total relaxation and renewal.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $185</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;opa&rsquo;a (&ldquo;To Complete&rdquo;) Detoxifying Body Massage &amp; Algae Wrap</h2>
					<p>Unrefined, sun-dried green clay blended with the purest spirulina defines this experience. Finding balance and clarity using organic myrtle, lemon and juniper combined with sandalwood and olive stone to regenerate, oxygenate and clarify your skin. Skin will be restored, rehydrated and protected by our organic myrtle, cypress, hyssop, juniper, rosemary and other healing plants and flowers, leaving it feeling pure, clean, firm and smooth. A Swedish massage finishes this age-defying treatment.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $185</strong></p>
					<h1>Add-On Treatments</h1>
					<h2>Mālama Maka (&ldquo;Care for the Eyes&rdquo;) Soothing &amp; Healing Eye Treatment</h2>
					<p>Applied during mask resting time. Treat and revive tired or stressed eyes with Amala&rsquo;s mineral-rich eye pack. This eye pack will work to restore tone and elasticity and assist in minimizing dark circles, puffiness and fine lines while regenerating and oxygenating your skin. The delicate eye area will be soothed, remineralized and rehydrated by our organic seed oils, crafted from plants and flowers which are vital for the health and repair of our skin.</p>
					<p><strong>$40</strong></p>
					<h2>&lsquo;Ānainai Pa&rsquo;akai (&ldquo;To Scrub with Salt&rdquo;) Sea Mineral Salt Scrub</h2>
					<p>A perfect add-on to any massage. Unrefined, mineral rich sea salt will gently buff away dry flaky skin, leaving your body silky smooth.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes - $65</strong></p>
					<h2>&lsquo;Ānainai &lsquo;Ili (&ldquo;To Scrub the Skin&rdquo;) Dry Brush Treatment</h2>
					<p>Stimulate the lymphatic system with this massage add-on. Dry skin will be brushed off, while stimulating the lymphatic system to help create perfect balance.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes - $50</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-body-treatments-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Body Treatments</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-body-treatments.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="81" position="4" sitemapId="4.2.1.3" sitemapTitle="Facials">
					<title>Facials</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-facials</slug>
						<pageTitle>Facials</pageTitle>
						<description>We believe that natural beauty is best restored using natural remedies.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hāna, spa treatment, spa, facial, natural beauty, skin care, heal, healing herbs</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Pālā&rsquo;au &lsquo;Ili (Heal the Skin with Herbs) Skin Care]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>We believe that natural beauty is best restored using natural remedies. At Travaasa Hāna we call it Pālā&lsquo;au &lsquo;lli (heal the skin with herbs). Let us create a facial expressly for you and your skin type, then lay back and relax as we soothe, heal and clarify your skin with local clay, wild-crafted oils, plants, minerals and flowers.</p>
					<h2>Ka &lsquo;Oi (&ldquo;The Best&rdquo;) Most Pure Facial</h2>
					<p>Throughout time, blue lotus has symbolized purity of mind and body. Blue lotus, and other healing plants, seed oils and flowers such as jasmine, papaya, coco bean, green tea and green algae inspired this balancing, clarifying and restorative treatment. Indian Rassoul clay is incorporated for its deep-cleansing and healing properties. Our signature Vedic Marma Cleansing Technique, combined with wild-crafted bamboo, tiger grass and ginger, provides essential nutrition and replenishes amino acids to purify the skin as it restores balance. The rare blue lotus provides essential nutrition for a pure, healthy complexion. Great for all skin types.</p>
					<p><strong>90 minutes - $195</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;oma&rsquo;ema&rsquo;e (&ldquo;To Purify&rdquo;) Oil Control Facial</h2>
					<p>Restore balance, clarity and radiance to skin inspired by the healing plants and flowers of the Islands. Fair-trade rice germ, blue lotus, bamboo, algae extract and green and white clays help control excessive oil production and remove clogging impurities from skin. Wild-crafted tiger grass, tonka, macadamia and organic aloe, ginger and lemon help heal blemishes and promote clear skin. Organic green and white teas provide antioxidant protection, soothe skin and even skin tone for a pure, clear and healthy complexion. Perfect for oily and combination skin.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;opahe&rsquo;e (&ldquo;To Hydrate&rdquo;) Deep Moisturizing Facial</h2>
					<p>Quench dry, dehydrated skin with our organic, fair-trade cultivated and custom-distilled jasmine, along with organic papaya, jojoba and shea butter. Soothing fruits and healing herbs will restore lasting hydration and elasticity while protecting skin from free radical damage. Fine lines and uneven skin texture are smoothed by clove bud, lychee, rosewood and turmeric. The healing power of jasmine and other South Pacific plant ingredients replenish and sustain the skin&rsquo;s moisture and pono (balance) for a silky smooth texture and healthy, even tone. Essential for dehydrated, tired or jetlagged skin.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;omālena (&ldquo;To Tighten&rdquo;) Firming Facial</h2>
					<p>Nourish, rejuvenate and firm your skin with this luxurious and highly effective facial. A combination of organic jasmine, avocado, macadamia nut and papaya gently hydrates. The perfect blend of organic cocoa bean, acerola, damask rose, sandalwood and hibiscus rejuvenates and brightens your skin. Restorative fruits and plants such as andiroba, neroli and buriti will smooth fine lines and renew elasticity of the skin. Sun-dried sea algae, organic aloe, green coffee oil and licorice root trap and remove impurities, leaving your skin firmer, brighter with a more radiant and youthful skin tone.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;omalu (&ldquo;To Protect&rdquo;) Hāna Remineralizing Facial</h2>
					<p>Unrefined white and pink clays blended with the purest spirulina define this facial experience. Healing organic plants and flowers nourish parched skin. Inherent minerals will regenerate, oxygenate and deeply stimulate your skin. Your skin will gently absorb the minerals, vitamins and moisture from our organic cocoa bean, acai, andiroba, brazil nut, island plants and flowers, leaving skin brighter, firmer, smoother, more youthful. Great for all skin types, especially mature or long-term sun damaged skin.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $140</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;opiha (&ldquo;To Replenish&rdquo;) Soothing Skin Facial</h2>
					<p>Sun-dried, white clay has been used by indigenous cultures throughout the ages for its healing, cooling, anti-inflammatory and regenerative properties. Our organic, botanical facial uses white clay to calm and nurture sensitive or overexposed skin back to healthy balance. Organic jasmine, shea butter, aloe, rose, papaya and other healing plants and flowers will replenish the skin&rsquo;s moisture level and restore a healthy, even tone. Sensitive skin and sunburned skin will also benefit from this facial.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Kāne (Gentleman&rsquo;s) Facial</h2>
					<p>The healing blue lotus has come to symbolize purity and balance. Our gentleman&rsquo;s deeply cleansing and hydrating facial employs wild-crafted blue lotus, algae extract, rice germ, bamboo, ginger, lemon and tiger grass to exfoliate and purify the skin and decongest pores. Perfect for a man&rsquo;s skin, this facial provides the full spectrum of skin benefits as nature intended.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>
					<h2>Hō&rsquo;ae&rsquo;ae (&ldquo;To Make Soft&rdquo;) Purifying Back Treatment</h2>
					<p>Restore balance, clarity and radiance to your skin with this back treatment inspired by the healing properties of rice germ, blue lotus, bamboo, algae extract and green and white clays. Control excessive oil production and remove clogging impurities from skin. Tiger grass and lemon help heal blemishes and promote clear skin; green and white teas provide antioxidant protection, soothe skin and even skin tone for a pure, healthy complexion.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $135</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-facials-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Facials</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-facials.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="82" position="5" sitemapId="4.2.1.4" sitemapTitle="Hands, Feet and Scalp">
					<title><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-hands-feet-and-scalp</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></pageTitle>
						<description>Head, hands, feet, they’re how we engage the world and perhaps our hardest working parts. Our natural treatments strengthen and energize, leaving you feeling healthy and nourished.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, head, scalp, hands, feet, treatment</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Hāna Hydrating Hand Treatment</h2>
					<p>Soften and smooth dehydrated skin with the fruits and flowers of Southeast Asia. Hands are exfoliated with organic olive stone and salt, and then wrapped in a detoxifying myrtle and clay mask. Organic jasmine, papaya, shea butter and jojoba strengthen the skin&rsquo;s moisture barrier and help prevent signs of aging for smooth, healthy hands.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes, $65</strong></p>
					<h2>Hāna Detoxifying Foot Treatment</h2>
					<p>Myrtle has a long reputation for deep cleansing. Feet are soaked in organic myrtle salt water, exfoliated with organic olive stone and salt and wrapped in a detoxifying myrtle and clay mask. Our organic myrtle, cypress, hyssop and juniper will purify, cleanse, refresh, smooth and refine the skin, leaving your feet feeling silky, smooth and energized.</p>
					<p><strong>30 minutes - $75</strong></p>
					<h2>Aromatherapy Scalp Treatment</h2>
					<p>This wonderful scalp treatment uses herbal oils of cinnamon and clove to stimulate and nourish your hair and scalp.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-hands-feet-scalp-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Hands, Feet & Scalp]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-hands-feet-scalp.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="83" position="6" sitemapId="4.2.1.5" sitemapTitle="Massage Therapy">
					<title>Massage Therapy</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-massage-therapy</slug>
						<pageTitle>Massage Therapy</pageTitle>
						<description>Our therapists perform a range of rapturous, transportive massages capable of satisfying whatever your body needs, whether it’s a health kick of energy or deep, stress-relieving calm.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, massage, Swedish massage, therapy, tension, stress</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Massage Therapy</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Swedish Massage</h2>
					<p>This deeply relaxing and soothing massage uses long, flowing strokes to help reduce tension and stress, ease stiffness and gently increase circulation. Our signature coconut, rice bran and monoi oil is used during this massage.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $130/$185</strong></p>
					<h2>Deep Tissue Massage</h2>
					<p>Melt away deep-seated tension and pain. This massage will release muscle fatigue and toxicity, help to realign your posture and increase range of motion. Our signature rice bran, coconut and monoi oil is used during this massage.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $140/$195</strong></p>
					<h2>Hāpai (Pre-Natal) Massage</h2>
					<p>Perfect for that special mom-to-be. This massage can be performed in all stages of pregnancy and is designed to reduce fluid retention, increase muscle tone and soothe aching backs and necks.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $130</strong></p>
					<h2>Traditional Thai Massage</h2>
					<p>This ancient healing art of Thailand uses gentle compression, acupressure on specific energy lines, rhythmic stretching and warm herbal compresses. The yoga of massage. Thai massage garments are provided.</p>
					<p><strong>90 or 120 minutes - $195/$250</strong></p>
					<h2>Pōhaku Wela Hot Stone</h2>
					<p>In the traditions of Hawai&rsquo;i, smooth heated stones apply the elements of earth, air, fire and water to achieve a healing, centering, rejuvenating treatment as muscle tension melts.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $140/$195</strong></p>
					<h2>Hawaiian Lomilomi</h2>
					<p>Lomilomi is a powerful native Hawaiian healing tradition. Rhythmic strokes, joint movement and deep kneading open the body and soothe the soul. Enjoy your choice of aromatherapy signature oil blends - $10 additional.</p>
					<p><strong>60 or 90 minutes - $130/$185</strong></p>
					<h2>Reflexology</h2>
					<p>Reflexology uses a specific touch to stimulate points along meridian paths over the entire body. This treatment begins with a dry brush treatment over the feet and lower leg, followed by a detoxifying foot soak using organic myrtle, fig and juniper. A soothing hand and foot massage completes this treatment. Not recommended for pregnant women.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $130</strong></p>
					<h2>Aquatic Renewal Therapy</h2>
					<p>Experience a whole new level of bodywork in Maui&rsquo;s first resort aquatic therapy pool. Drift into deep levels of relaxation. As you float and stretch in the therapist&rsquo;s arms without the pull of gravity, the warm water supports your body evenly, releases tension and produces a deep sense of renewed well-being. A bathing suit is required.</p>
					<p><strong>60 minutes - $14</strong></p>
					<h2>Hō&rsquo;a&rsquo;ala (&ldquo;To Make Fragrant&rdquo;) Aromatherapy Oil</h2>
					<p>Added to any massage treatment.</p>
					<p><strong>$10</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-massage-therapy-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Massage Therapy</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-massage-therapy.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="84" position="7" sitemapId="4.2.1.6" sitemapTitle="Waxing Services">
					<title>Waxing Services</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-Waxing Services</slug>
						<pageTitle>Waxing Services</pageTitle>
						<description>xxx</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, waxing</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Waxing Services</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Lip</h2>
					<p><strong>15 minutes - $20</strong></p>
					<h2>Brow Shape</h2>
					<p><strong>15 minutes - $25</strong></p>
					<h2>Full Leg</h2>
					<p><strong>90 minutes &ndash; Starting at $90</strong></p>
					<h2>Bikini</h2>
					<p><strong>30 minutes &ndash; Starting at $75</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-waxing-services-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Waxing Services</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-waxing-services.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="85" position="8" sitemapId="4.2.1.7" sitemapTitle="Special Packages">
					<title>Special Packages</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-special-packages</slug>
						<pageTitle>Special Packages</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa provides you with different rate and package selections so that you can make the most of your time at Hāna. These special offerings help you design a journey that’s just right for you.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, special packages, couple’s vacation, couple’s getaway, couple’s escape.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Special Packages</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Hāna Couple&rsquo;s Escape</h2>
					<p>Relax together, in the privacy of our couple&rsquo;s spa suite. Share any 60-minute massage, followed by a 90 minute Body Treatment of your choice. Price per couple, does not include gratuity.</p>
					<p><strong>$590 per couple</strong></p>
					<h2>Ho&rsquo;okaulike (Total Balance)</h2>
					<p>Choose any 60-minute facial followed by any 90-minute massage. Does not include gratuity.</p>
					<p><strong>$285 per person</strong></p>
					<h2>Mālama Kino Package (Total Care)</h2>
					<p>Regular massage and body therapies increase circulation and promote overall health, giving your body, mind and spirit a renewed sense of well-being. Choose up to eight 60-minute treatments from our spa menu and enjoy the benefits of wellness. Allow us to customize a package for you. Speak to your spa concierge for help in designing your ultimate spa experience. This package is available for more than one person and must be prepaid. There are no refunds or reimbursements for unused treatments. Guests may use this package any time during their stay. Price does not include gratuity.</p>
					<p><strong>$950 per cottage</strong></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-special-packages-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Special Packages</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-special-packages.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="2" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="86" position="9" sitemapId="4.2.1.8" sitemapTitle="Spa Facilities">
					<title>Spa Facilities</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-spa-facilities</slug>
						<pageTitle>Spa Facilities</pageTitle>
						<description>Our spa facilities submerse you in luxury and bring the beauty of Hāna into your relaxation and wellness experience. We invite you to enjoy our complete range of services and amenities for both men and women.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, spa, luxury, wellness, experience, service, amenities</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Spa Facilities</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy our well-appointed men&rsquo;s and women&rsquo;s locker rooms complete with steam rooms, cold plunge pool, indoor and outdoor showers, robes, slippers, towels and personal amenities. Beverages, herbal tea and fresh fruit are provided in the relaxation lounge. Relax in our outdoor, lava-rock whirlpool and lounge overlooking Hāna Bay in a tropical garden setting. Browse our spa shop, which features a full line of nurturing products, clothing, books, music, jewelry, teas and more.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-spa-facilities-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Spa Facilities</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-spa-facilities.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="3" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="true" id="87" position="1" sitemapId="4.2.2" sitemapTitle="Dining">
					<title>Dining</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-dining-overview</slug>
						<pageTitle>Dining</pageTitle>
						<description>At Travaasa you’ll find organic, locally-sourced produce, meat, fish and dairy.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Hawaiian, Asian, Polynesian, health-conscious, vegetarian, vegan, nourish.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Dining Overview</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Nourishment</h2>
					<p>With the incredible abundance and inspiration of Hāna to draw from, our Executive Chef has created a dining experience that&rsquo;s pure Travaasa &ndash; a celebration of life and the bounty of the earth that nourishes us body and soul. He&rsquo;s coined a name for his eclectic, creative culinary style: Hāna Fusion, a combination of techniques from classical to innovative blending bold flavors with a focus on in-season, local ingredients.</p>
					<p>The menu incorporates many diverse layers of culinary influence central to Hawaiian culture. Alongside signature local dishes, you&rsquo;ll find elements of Asian and Old World European cuisine. Here at Travaasa Hāna, it all gets mixed up in a delicious m&eacute;lange as our chef creates familiar yet unique dishes with a Polynesian flair. And in keeping with the health-conscious ethos of the Hawaiian people, we also offer an extensive selection of gourmet vegetarian and vegan foods. Everything we serve is made from scratch with health and balance in mind.</p>
					<p>During your stay you can expect to savor a wide range of inventive, ambrosial dishes, such as our own Pohole Fern Shoot Salad, a native Hawaiian favorite. Fish wrapped in Ti Leaves. Seaweed salad. Taro. Fish smoked with guava and mango wood. Lilikoi Mahi with Hawaiian sweet potato and ginger lime coconut sauce. And an Open-faced Smoked Chicken Salad Sandwich on house-made bread with a locally grown sprout salad.</p>
					<p>Travaasa is all about the experience, a reminder that life is for living, and living well, and we always want you to leave happy. Dine with us and that philosophy is clear with every bite.</p><p><em>Guests of our Garden View suites are welcome to enjoy all our dining options on an a la carte basis</em></p>
					<h2>Eating Well</h2>
					<p>The Islands are a land rich with nature&rsquo;s bounty. And we only select fresh, organic, locally-sourced produce, fish, meat and dairy. Premium foods that are in-season and in our area to bring you only the finest sustainable breakfast, lunch and dinner options. At Travaasa Hāna we like to nourish, not only the spirit, but also the body. Because good food means good health.</p>
					<p><em>Guests of our Garden View suites are welcome to enjoy all our dining options on an a la carte basis</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-dining-overview-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Dining Overview</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-dining-overview.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="88" position="2" sitemapId="4.2.2.1" sitemapTitle="Dining Options">
					<title>Dining Options</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-dining-options</slug>
						<pageTitle>Dining Options</pageTitle>
						<description>Enjoy breakfast, lunch and dinner in our Ka’uiki dining room or Paniolo café.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, breakfast, lunch, dinner, fish, chicken, salads, burgers, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, Kauiki dining room, Paniolo café, Hāna Town Center, roadhouse.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Dining Options</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy breakfast, lunch or dinner in our dining room, Ka&rsquo;uiki, as well as lighter fare in our caf&eacute;, Paniolo Lounge. Or engage in spirited and always unpredictable discussions at our Chef&rsquo;s Table.</p>
					<p>You may also want to stroll up to the Hāna Ranch Restaurant in the Hāna Town Center. It&rsquo;s an eclectic ranch-style roadhouse featuring Polynesian inspired ranch fare. Enjoy fish, chicken, salads and burgers. There&rsquo;s even a take out window for those on the go.</p>
					<p><em>Guests of our Garden View suites are welcome to enjoy all our dining options on an a la carte basis</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-dining-options-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Dining Options</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-dining-options.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="89" position="3" sitemapId="4.2.2.2" sitemapTitle="Libations">
					<title>Libations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-libations</slug>
						<pageTitle>Libations</pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa serves organic, biodynamic wines and craft and organic beers.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Tedeschi Vineyards, Maui Brewing Company, wine, beer, organic, biodynamic, handcrafted lagers and ales, Mai Tai.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Libations</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p><strong>Wine</strong> We offer a distinctive and varied wine list that mirrors our environmental values by featuring organic, biodynamic and sustainable wines made by boutique producers. The practice of biodynamics in winemaking has been gaining in popularity and biodynamic wines have stronger, clearer, more vibrant tastes, as well as wines that remain drinkable longer.</p>
					<p><strong>Beer</strong> Sticking with our locally-sourced credo, we offer handcrafted lagers and ales from the Maui Brewing Company. Their Bikini Blonde lager, Big Swell IPA and Coconut Porter are brewed from the finest natural and local ingredients. We also stock an exceptional selection of imported beers.</p>
					<p><strong>Cocktails</strong> When in Hawai&rsquo;i do as the Hawaiians do. Try a Hāna Mai Tai made with fresh juices and other Hāna favorites like the pineapple mojito and the Hāna Highway Delight.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-libations-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Libations</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-libations.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="3" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="90" position="4" sitemapId="4.2.2.3" sitemapTitle="Executive Chef">
					<title>Executive Chef</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-executive-chef</slug>
						<pageTitle>Executive Chef</pageTitle>
						<description>xxx</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, executive chef</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Executive Chef, Barry Villiarimo</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Chef Barry Villiarimo returned to Hāna in 2010, coming full circle to where his career began. Raised in Hāna, Chef Barry spent the previous twenty years heading up some of the finest hotel restaurants on the West Coast, including the Westin Bonaventure Hotel &amp; Suites in Los Angeles.</p>
					<p>With a focus on farm-to-table cuisine, coupled with a blending of indigenous Hawaiian ingredients whenever possible, Chef Barry&rsquo;s attention to healthy eating is the perfect complement to Travaasa Hāna&rsquo;s commitment to our guest&rsquo;s culinary enjoyment, health and well being.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-executive-chef-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Executive Chef</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-executive-chef.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="4" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="true" id="91" position="1" sitemapId="4.2.3" sitemapTitle="Accommodations: Garden View Suites">
					<title>Accommodations</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-accommodations-garden-view-suites</slug>
						<pageTitle>Accommodations: Garden View Suites</pageTitle>
						<description>Our Garden View stays feature spectacular scenic overlooks and offer a la carte dining, spa and other great Travaasas.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Garden View Suites, Garden Pool, fitness room.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Accommodations: Garden View Suites</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>There are only 52 miles between Hāna and the airport, yet the trip often takes people a full day. That&rsquo;s because the beauty of the area is so extraordinary it&rsquo;s impossible to stay in the car. You simply have to stop, breathe deeply, and take it in.</p>
					<p>Our Garden View stay options are wonderful for day-trippers as well as couples and families planning a stay in Hāna. The amenities are pure Travaasa, giving guests the perfect setting to relax and reflect after a day exploring Hāna&rsquo;s spectacular beauty, plus access to the features and services that make Travaasa Hāna as much a journey as a destination. Travaasa Hāna Garden Suites are family-friendly, and open to adults and children of all ages.</p>
					<p>Choose from your choice of our Garden View suite, or for families, a luxurious, home-style stay in our Waikoloa Family Suites.</p>
					<p><em>* If you&rsquo;re looking for an all-inclusive experience, please take a look at our <a href="hana-experiences" class="address_ajax">Sea Ranch</a> stay options.</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-accomodations-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Garden View Accommodations</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-accomodations.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="92" position="2" sitemapId="4.2.3.1" sitemapTitle="Garden View Suites">
					<title>Garden View Suites</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-suites</slug>
						<pageTitle>Garden View Suites</pageTitle>
						<description>Garden View Suites offer à la carte dining, spa and activities and overlook flowering native trees and tropical gardens.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Garden View Suites, Garden Pool, fitness room.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Garden View Suites</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Each Garden Suite overlooks the lush, immaculate landscape of Hāna.&nbsp; This is the real Hawai&lsquo;i with flowering native trees and tropical gardens. Inside, you&rsquo;ll be equally pleased with the surroundings of your oversized junior suite. It captures the eclectic mix of Hawaiian history and culture through the use of materials and colors. All appointments and fixtures are first class with each suite featuring a relaxing sitting area and wet bar.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-suites-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Garden View Suites</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-suites.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="4" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="93" position="3" sitemapId="4.2.3.2" sitemapTitle="Waikoloa Family Suites">
					<title>Waikoloa Family Suites</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-waikoloa-family-suites</slug>
						<pageTitle>Waikoloa Family Suites</pageTitle>
						<description>Experience all the comforts of paradise with your family in this luxuriously appointed three-bedroom, two-bath condominium.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, Hāna Bay, Waikoloa, family suite, family vacation, family getaway, Kauiki</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Waikoloa Family Suites</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Adjacent to our enticing 3-hole pitch &amp; putt golf course, these spacious units are perfect for families &ndash; because they feel just like home. The elegant appointments include a large dining area; gourmet kitchen featuring top-of-the-line appliances, granite counter tops, cherry wood cabinetry with wine storage refrigerator; and large bathrooms with both shower and tub.</p>
					<p>Wake up each morning to the breathtaking Hāna sunrise and savor your panoramic view of beautiful Hāna Bay on the Pacific Ocean all day long. These suites are conveniently located near The Spa at Travaasa Hāna, shops and Kauiki Restaurant.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-family-suites-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Waikoloa Family Suites</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-family-suites.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="5" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="true" id="94" position="3" sitemapId="4.2.4" sitemapTitle="Rates and Packages: Garden View Suites">
					<title><![CDATA[Rates & Packages]]></title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-rates-and-packages-garden-view-suites</slug>
						<pageTitle><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Garden View Suites]]></pageTitle>
						<description>Travaasa offers different rate and package selections, allowing you to customize your experience and make the most of your time with us.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, garden view, rates, packages</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1><![CDATA[Rates & Packages: Garden View Suites]]></h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Garden Suite Sunrise Package</h2>
					<p>Experience Travaasa and Hāna in one of our oversized junior Garden Suite rooms. Included with your accommodations is a generous breakfast and access to many of the cultural activities featured at the Makana Center.</p>
					<p><strong>Rates begin at $360, double occupancy</strong><em> (tax and service charge not included)</em></p>
					<p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<h2>Garden Suite</h2>
					<p>Our Garden Suite offers an oversized junior suite with relaxing sitting area and wet bar. Enjoy a luxurious stay in a room overlooking lushly landscaped Hāna-Maui grounds, flowering native trees and tropical gardens, and have access to activities at the Makana Center.</p>
					<p><strong>Rates begin at $325, double occupancy</strong> <em>(tax and service charge not included)</em></p>
					<p><a href="https://gc.synxis.com/rez.aspx?Hotel=26987&Chain=10237&template=HNMHM&shell=HNMHM2" TARGET="_blank"><strong>Book Now</strong></a></p>
					<p><em>Please note that all guests on the Sea Ranch Cottage side of the property must be 16 years or older (except during our Family Weeks). Families and children under 16 are welcome in all of our Garden View suite accommodations.</em></p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-rates-packages-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption><![CDATA[Garden View Rates & Packages]]></thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-garden-view-rates-packages.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="6" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="true" id="95" position="1" sitemapId="4.2.5" sitemapTitle="Makana Activity Center">
					<title>Makana Center</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-Makana Activity Center</slug>
						<pageTitle>Makana Center</pageTitle>
						<description>xxx</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Makana Center</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Tucked in the heart of the Travaasa Hāna reception area, the Makana Center is the place to go to sign up for all classes (Travaasas) and Garden View-eligible classes&mdash;hula, lei making and &lsquo;ukulele. You can also find books (which you can check out) on Hāna and Maui, maps and historical artifacts here. A mother lode of information on all things Travaasa Hāna, it&rsquo;s your go-to destination to take advantage of all that we have to offer.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-makana-activity-center-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Makana Center</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-makana-activity-center.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="6" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="96" position="2" sitemapId="4.2.5.1" sitemapTitle="Hula">
					<title>Hula</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-hula</slug>
						<pageTitle>Hula</pageTitle>
						<description>Every hula tells a story and you’ll learn the hand and foot movements that go along with telling it.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, hula, story, cultural guides, teacher, childhood, generation, dance, traditions, aina, kai.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Hula</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Every hula tells a story, and you&rsquo;ll learn all the graceful hand and foot movements that go along with telling it. Hula is more than just a dance&mdash;it is something that links Hawaiians to <em>&lsquo;Āina</em> (land) and <em>Kai</em> (ocean) and in broader terms, to the story of life. Hula is traditionally a way that stories and traditions were passed from generation to generation. Originally, hula was danced by men, but now it is performed by both men and women. You&rsquo;ll learn a story from one of our cultural guides, your <em>kumu</em> (teacher) who&rsquo;s been practicing hula since childhood.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-hula-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Hula</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-hula.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="6" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="97" position="3" sitemapId="4.2.5.2" sitemapTitle="Lei Making">
					<title>Lei Making</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-lei-making</slug>
						<pageTitle>Lei Making</pageTitle>
						<description>Leis are used to celebrate all occasions in Hawai’I, and you’ll learn lei-making techniques in our classes.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, lei, Plumeria, classes, techniques, blooms, Ti Leaf, Kukui Nut, lei wili, lei hili, lei kui pololei.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Lei Making</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>You were probably charmed by the <em>Ti</em> leaf <em>lei</em> adorned with Plumeria blooms you received upon arrival, or maybe you&rsquo;re still wearing the <em>Kukui</em> Nut <em>lei</em> we gave you. Learn how to make your own <em>Ti</em> leaf <em>lei</em>, or string Plumeria blooms for a colorful, wonderfully scented <em>lei</em>. <em>Leis</em> are traditionally used to celebrate all occasions in Hawai&rsquo;i, and we have a variety of classes where you can learn different techniques, from<em> lei wili</em> (twisting),<em> lei hili</em> (braiding),<em> lei kui pololei</em> (strung with a needle) and more.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-lei-making-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Lei Making</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-lei-making.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				<page section="6" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="false" id="98" position="4" sitemapId="4.2.5.3" sitemapTitle="Ukulele">
					<title>'Ukulele</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-ukulele</slug>
						<pageTitle>'Ukulele</pageTitle>
						<description>Learn how to play the 'ukulele.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, ukulele, Portuguese, 19th century, chords, song, lū‘au, luau, instrument, Noe Noe, gift shop.</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>'Ukulele</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>First introduced to Hawaiians by the Portuguese in the 19th century, the &lsquo;Ukulele is now more well known as a Hawaiian instrument. You&rsquo;ll learn basic chords, and before long, you&rsquo;ll be playing a well-known song. We&rsquo;ll send you home with sheet music, a little bit of history about the &lsquo;Ukulele, and we even sell small &lsquo;Ukulele in our Noe Noe gift shop&mdash;just in case you want to serenade family and friends at your next lū&lsquo;au.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-ukulele-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>'Ukulele</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-ukulele.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
				<page section="7" primarySection="2" secondaryNav="true" id="100" position="3" sitemapId="4.2.7" sitemapTitle="Off-Property Excursions">
					<title>Off-Property Excursions</title>
					<meta>
						<slug>hana-garden-view-off-property-excursions</slug>
						<pageTitle>Off-Property Excursions</pageTitle>
						<description>Off-property excursions let you get to know Hāna and Maui.</description>
						<keywords>travaasa, Hāna, hana, black-sand beach, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, swimming, horseback riding, cultural center, ancestors, Hāna Bay, Maui Stables, Ono Organic Farms, Wai Anapanapa State Park, off-property, excursions, Hāna Cultural Center, Kahanu Garden, ‘Ōhe’o Gulch at Haleakalā National Park, Seven Pools, Waimoku Falls</keywords>
					</meta>
					<h1>Off-Property Excursions</h1>
					<copy><![CDATA[<h2>Hāna Town Center</h2>
					<p>Get a glimpse of community life by taking a stroll through the Town Center and browse the shops. The bank, post office, Hāna Ranch Restaurant, florist, Hāna Ranch Store and several gift shops are located here. Town Center is just a five-minute walk from the hotel.</p>
					<h2>Wai&rsquo;ānapanapa State Park</h2>
					<p>Walk along the ancient &ldquo;King&rsquo;s Trail,&rdquo; explore a legendary freshwater cave, discover important archeological sites, visit Maui&rsquo;s only black-sand beach and of course, it all overlooks the Pacific Ocean.</p>
					<h2>Hāna Bay</h2>
					<p><em>Kapueokahi</em> (the lone owl) is commonly referred to as &ldquo;Hāna Bay.&rdquo; It was the major shipping port for the sugar companies. Today, this quarter-mile slice of black and white sand is a favorite with local families for swimming, snorkeling and strolling. Complimentary snorkeling equipment is available at the Concierge Desk.</p>
					<h2>Hāna Cultural Center</h2>
					<p>Just a short walk from Travaasa Hāna, the Cultural Center houses a fascinating collection of historical photos, documents and artifacts. The gift shop helps support the collections and any donation is greatly appreciated.</p>
					<p>Open Monday &ndash; Friday 10:00 a.m.&ndash;4:00 pm.</p>
					<h2>Kahanu Garden</h2>
					<p>The Garden is home to some of Hawai&rsquo;i&rsquo;s most precious treasures. <em>Pi&rsquo;ilanihale</em>, a <em>heiau</em> or temple, is believed to be the largest man-made, pre-Western structure in all of Polynesia. Self-guided tours are offered Monday&ndash;Friday 10:00 a.m.&ndash;2:00 p.m. by the National Tropical Botanical Gardens. Guided tours are available on Saturdays by appointment. Advance reservations are required.</p>
					<h2>&lsquo;Ōhe&rsquo;o Gulch at Haleakalā National Park</h2>
					<p>The Park features the famous &ldquo;Pools of &#332;heo&rdquo; &ndash; a series of cascading pools leading to the ocean. The Waimoku Falls Trail is a five-mile round trip hike that takes you through a bamboo forest to the 400-foot Waimoku Falls. NOTE: The Park is approximately 11 miles from Hāna town and we urge you to drive there with caution and heed all caution signs while at the park.</p>
					<h2>ONO Organic Farms</h2>
					<p>This family-owned farm where everything is hand picked and certified organic is aptly named. ONO is the Hawaiian word for delicious. You&rsquo;ll tour this pure organic paradise and enjoy a tropical fruit tasting adventure by sampling 12 varieties of tropical fruit and ONO-grown coffee.</p>
					<h2>Maui Stables</h2>
					<p>Go on a historical and cultural horseback ride through the ancient unspoiled landscape of Maui. This isn&rsquo;t your typical stable. Maui Stables is native owned and operated. The <em>Alaka&rsquo;i</em> (guides) and <em>Kako&rsquo;o</em> (apprentice) who accompany you can trace their family roots back hundreds of years. Each tour will begin with a <em>pule</em> (prayer) and <em>oli</em>, or call to our ancestors. Throughout the ride they&rsquo;ll share stories of their ancestors and the land.</p>]]>
					</copy>
					<thumbImg>images/site/hana-off-property-excursions-t.jpg</thumbImg>
					<thumbCaption>Off-Property Excursions</thumbCaption>
					<mainImg>images/site/hana-off-property-excursions.jpg</mainImg>
					<imageCaption></imageCaption>
					<Storybook></Storybook>
						<pdf_downloads>
							<pdf>
								<title></title>
								<url></url>
							</pdf>
						</pdf_downloads>
				</page>
				
			</secondaryPages>
		</hana>
	</pages>
