<?xml version="1.0" standalone='yes' ?>
	<pages>
		<intro sitemapId="0.0" sitemapTitle="Landing Page">
			<meta>
				<slug></slug>
				<pageTitle>Travaasa - Real Travel for Real Experiences.</pageTitle>
				<description>Rediscover the magic of travel with Travaasa Austin, Texas or Hāna, Maui.</description>
				<keywords>travaasa, travel, resorts, hana, hāna, hawaii, austin, texas, Austin resort, Austin spa, travaasa Austin, Austin spa resort, experiential, hotel, Austin hotel, Austin conference center, Austin group meeting</keywords>
			</meta>
			<backgroundImages>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/splash_BG.jpg</src>
					<caption></caption>
				</image>
			</backgroundImages>
			<mainContent>
				<h1><![CDATA[Travaasa&ndash;a collection of experiential destination hotels.]]></h1>
				<copy><![CDATA[<p class="home_content">We created Travaasa so you can Travaasa. So you can rediscover the magic of travel. The art of the journey. Have memories to glow by. Travaasa opens you up to your physical, spiritual and mental world with happenings you'll remember forever, lessons and delights that will become a part of you forever. And it all starts at our gorgeous Hāna, Hawaii and Austin, Texas, destination hotels. Your Travaasa experience begins and ends with one thought: Only at Travaasa could I live that.</p>]]>
					</copy>
				<learnMoreUrl></learnMoreUrl>
			</mainContent>
		</intro>
		
		<index sitemapId="0.0" sitemapTitle="Home Page">
			<meta>
				<slug></slug>
				<pageTitle>Travaasa - Real Travel for Real Experiences.</pageTitle>
				<description>Rediscover the magic of travel with Travaasa Austin, Texas or Hāna, Maui.</description>
				<keywords>travaasa, travel, resorts, hana, hāna, hawaii, austin, texas, Austin resort, Austin spa, travaasa Austin, Austin spa resort, experiential, hotel, Austin hotel, Austin conference center, Austin group meeting</keywords>
			</meta>
			<backgroundImages>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-3.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Sunrise view from Travaasa Hāna&rsquo;s Sea Ranch Cottages.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-4.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Throw net at Hāna Bay.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-1.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Soak it all in at the infinity pool at Travaasa Austin.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-2.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>After a relaxing spa visit, you might not want to put your boots back on. </p>]]></caption>
				</image>			
			</backgroundImages>
			<slideshow instructions="because of the plugin, these actual need to be in reverse order of how they come out on the page">
					<image>
						<img>images/site/home-slideshow-04.png </img>
						<desc>The unspoiled Hawai'i coastline at Travaasa Hāna.</desc>
					</image>
					<image>
						<img>images/site/home-slideshow-02.png</img>
						<desc>From the moment you enter the gate, you know you're somewhere special at Traavasa Austin.</desc>
					</image>
					<image>
						<img>images/site/home-slideshow-03.png </img>
						<desc><![CDATA[Throw net at Hāna Bay.]]></desc>
					</image>
					<image>
						<img>images/site/home-slideshow-01.png</img>
						<desc>Travaasa experiences let you recapture the magic of travel.</desc>
					</image>
					
			</slideshow>
			<promos>
				<promo>
					<img>images/site/discover-hana.jpg</img>
					<h3>Discover Travaasa Hāna</h3>
					<copy><![CDATA[<a href="/hana/#/hana-rates-and-packages-sea-ranch-cottages">Save up to 33%</a> on November and December stays in Hāna, Maui.]]></copy>
					<learnMoreUrl></learnMoreUrl>
				</promo>
			</promos>
			<mainContent>
				<h1><![CDATA[Travaasa&ndash;a collection of experiential destination hotels.]]></h1>
				<copy><![CDATA[<p class="home_content">We wanted a place that would reawaken us. Intellectually, culturally, experientially. A place where we could learn, touch and do new things. A place we couldn’t find in our own backyard, or at the local spa or gym.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="home_content">We wanted a destination hotel that would give us the joy of the journey, the magic of arriving somewhere new and getting a sense of that place. No such place existed. So we decided to create it.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p class="home_content">Travaasa. Our name says it all, combining the words “travel” and “pravaasa,” a Sanskrit word meaning memorable journey. We created Travaasa for you to have memories to glow by. Begin your Travaasa journey here.</p>]]>
					</copy>
				<learnMoreUrl></learnMoreUrl>
			</mainContent>
		</index>
		<aboutUs  sitemapId="1.0" sitemapTitle="About Us">
			<meta>
				<slug></slug>
				<pageTitle>Travaasa Experiential Destination Hotels</pageTitle>
				<description>A destination hotel with world-class spa services where you can experience local food, landscapes, people and a real sense of place.</description>
				<keywords>travaasa, resort, spas, services, hotels, travel</keywords>
			</meta>
			<backgroundImages>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-3.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Sunrise view from Travaasa Hāna&rsquo;s Sea Ranch Cottages.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-4.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Throw net at Hāna Bay.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-1.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Soak it all in at the infinity pool at Travaasa Austin.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-2.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>After a relaxing spa visit, you might not want to put your boots back on. </p>]]></caption>
				</image>			
			</backgroundImages>
			<mainImage>
				<img>images/site/about-travaasa-crisman.png</img>
				<caption><![CDATA[<p>An experience that recaptures the magic of travel.</p>]]></caption>
			</mainImage>
			<mainContent>
				<h1><![CDATA[The Travaasa Vision]]></h1>
				<copy><![CDATA[<p>Travaasa. It&rsquo;s more than just a destination hotel with world-class spa services, food and beverages with local flavor, and breathtaking vistas. It&rsquo;s an experience that recaptures the magic of travel and gives you a memory to glow by.</p>
				<p>Travaasa is the best of what happens when you travel. The way a journey is supposed to be. Discovery of a place, of people, of yourself, of other languages. In our case, the languages of memory and storytelling.</p>
				<p>When you leave Travaasa, you leave with a story. Your story. And what a tale it will be. You&rsquo;ll experience local food, landscapes, people, and a real sense of place. At Travaasa Hāna you&rsquo;ll savor imu cooking and explore working plantations and ranches. Or maybe you&rsquo;ll just take a picnic lunch down to the beach&mdash;a natural, unspoiled beach&mdash;because, after all, this is your journey. You are on a memorable journey when you Travaasa and it&rsquo;s your choice to see, do and feel as much as you want.</p>
				<p>Our inspiration for Travaasa began with our own travel. Too many stays in too many cold, soulless concrete towers informed our philosophy. Too many hotels and resorts that looked the same from place to place and kept us from experiencing the real culture that lives outside our cookie-cutter rooms.</p>
				<p>We wanted a place that would reawaken us. Intellectually, culturally, experientially. A place where we could learn, touch and do new things. A place we couldn&rsquo;t find in our own backyard, or at the local spa or gym. In other words, we wanted the joy of the journey, the magic of arriving somewhere new and getting a sense of that place. We wanted spontaneous moments and the magic of surprise that travel is supposed to bring us.</p>
				<p>No such place existed. So we decided to create it.</p>
				]]></copy>
				<learnMoreUrl></learnMoreUrl>
			</mainContent>
			<promos>
				<promo>
					<h2>The Texas You've Always Dreamed Of</h2>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Your Travaasa starts the moment you find yourself in a car, winding down a spectacular Texas Hill Country road. The vista unravels like a color-saturated ribbon, leading you to a place unlike any other. The car stops. You have arrived. And what you&rsquo;ll find is an intimate gathering of buildings. A curated amount of casitas (rooms), because we&rsquo;re about your experience, your travel &ndash; not catering to hundreds of people.</p>]]></copy>
					<img>images/site/texas-dreamed-of-crisman.png</img>
					<learnMoreUrl>/austin/</learnMoreUrl>
					<learnMoreText>See our Austin Destination Hotel</learnMoreText>
				</promo>
				<promo>
					<h2>Customize Your Ultimate Getaway</h2>
					<copy><![CDATA[<p>Because this is your journey, you can customize your Travaasa experence anyway you want. Every day is different, and you'll always be surprised and delighted by what you find. Learn the Texas Two-Step one day and do a guided meditation the next &mdash; it's up to you. And with so much to see and do, you'll want to extend your stay.</p>]]></copy>
					<img>images/site/customize-getaway-crisman.png</img>
					<learnMoreUrl>/austin/rates-and-packages</learnMoreUrl>
					<learnMoreText>See our Travaasas</learnMoreText>
				</promo>
			</promos>
		</aboutUs>
		<contact  sitemapId="5.0" sitemapTitle="Contact Us">
			<meta>
				<slug>contact-us</slug>
				<pageTitle>Contact Us</pageTitle>
				<description> If you’re ready to Travaasa, start your journey today and experience the world in a different way.</description>
				<keywords>travaasa, contact, austin, hana, hāna, book, reservations, registration</keywords>
			</meta>
			<backgroundImages>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-3.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Sunrise view from Travaasa Hāna&rsquo;s Sea Ranch Cottages.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-4.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Throw net at Hāna Bay.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-1.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>Soak it all in at the infinity pool at Travaasa Austin.</p>]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<src>images/site/backgrounds/main-background-2.jpg</src>
					<caption><![CDATA[<p>After a relaxing spa visit, you might not want to put your boots back on. </p>]]></caption>
				</image>			
			</backgroundImages>
		</contact>
	</pages>
